<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Boulder | ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/blog/tags/boulder/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-29T21:24:50-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boulder Startup Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/boulder-startup-week"/>
    <updated>2013-05-17T15:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/boulder-startup-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday we took a group trip up to Boulder to participate in Boulder Startup Week, and even though it meant sacrificing a work day which we really need for our project, I&rsquo;m so glad we went.  I met a ton of really awesome people, got to take a look around some really interesting companies, and saw a new side of Boulder that I hadn&rsquo;t explored yet.</p>

<p>We started the day with a visit to the Boulder office of LivingSocial, which is composed only of LS developers.  It was really interesting to go back though - even though it&rsquo;s so different from the DC office, it still had that LS feel - the funky furniture converted into conference tables, the white chairs with the weird arm rests that never stayed in place.  I talked to two guys who worked there, one who worked on front end for user acquisition, and one who worked on back end for the LS Amazon partnership, and it was really interesting to see what they were working on, especially since I still recognized a lot of it.  We then went to QuickLeft to talk to some people on the team there and take a look around the offices, which were also really cool - especially the herb garden they have growing in the landscaping right next to the kitchen!</p>

<p>After that I met up with my friend Lauren, who still works at LivingSocial in Seattle, who was a fly-in for startup week, Ashe Dryden, and my husband Brock for lunch, and we were joined by my instructor Franklin.  I&rsquo;ve followed Ashe on Twitter for a long time, and it was really great to meet her in person finally, and seeing Lauren again (I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;d seen her since last September) was awesome.</p>

<p>After lunch we participated in the startup crawl and visited a bunch of different startups in the Pearl Street area.  There were so many amazing people we met, and I was really excited at how friendly and welcoming the whole community was, both the employees at the startups, and the other crawlers we met along the way.  There&rsquo;s so many people doing such diverse things, but everyone we met was really passionate about their work and the value they&rsquo;re bringing to their customers/clients.  I&rsquo;m so happy to be in this space; I feel like so many jobs are just that - just a job.  In the Ruby world, there&rsquo;s so much exciting stuff going on, and this really seems to be a community driven by passion.</p>

<p>I went to a Women in Tech dinner with Ashe, Lauren, and a few other people, and then we were off to Pivotal Labs for the Boulder Ruby Meetup.  Again, a ton of really engaging and passionate people there.  It&rsquo;s also really neat to have been to enough meetups at this point that I tend to see a lot of familiar faces and people to catch up with, and also meet new friends.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really excited to be a part of this community and to be joining it as an employee soon.  I can&rsquo;t believe we&rsquo;re down to 9 weeks left in gSchool - it&rsquo;ll be over so soon!  I&rsquo;m really excited to see what I&rsquo;ll be doing next, but it looks like there&rsquo;s lots of interesting options out there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
