<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Personal Project | ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/blog/tags/personal-project/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-26T23:32:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Personal TDD Challenge]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/my-personal-tdd-challenge"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T20:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/my-personal-tdd-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m not the happiest with middleman and want to address a few challenges, so I&rsquo;m creating a blog from scratch with Rails, hopefully without needing to reference the Blogger tutorial at all.</p>

<p>My challenges:</p>

<ol>
<li>Create an attractive design to practice front end development and showcase a blog I can be proud to show off - I really don&rsquo;t like the current look of my blog, and especially as I&rsquo;m increasingly going to be showing it off to potential employers, I need to stand behind and be proud of my work.</li>
<li>Practice my Rails skills from soup to nuts.  I love working on teams, but it necessitates touching only part of the code.  This will be good practice for me to make sure I understand the process beginning to end, and it&rsquo;s great practice before our individual project in two weeks!</li>
<li>Most importantly, 100% of the code will be written in TDD.  Literally not one line of code will be written without a failing test.  I haven&rsquo;t always been the best about adhering to strict TDD, and I need to get better - I know firsthand why it&rsquo;s important, and no skill is going to magically appear; I need to practice it.</li>
</ol>


<p>So&hellip; wish me luck!  Hopefully you&rsquo;ll see a finished product I&rsquo;m proud to stand by in no time :)  The biggest challenge I&rsquo;m anticipating is just finding time to work on it with all the other projects I&rsquo;m working on, but honestly, since there&rsquo;s no firm deadline and I am going at my own pace, working on it so far has almost felt like a break from everything else.  It is a good feeling - programming can be tough, but even just the small amount of time I&rsquo;ve put in so far reminds me of how much I love to do it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
