<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Sales Engine | ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/blog/tags/sales-engine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-26T23:52:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sales Engine Wrap-up]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/02/sales-engine-wrap-up"/>
    <updated>2013-02-22T10:06:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/02/sales-engine-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I still can&rsquo;t believe it&rsquo;s only been a week and a half since we started Sales Engine.  Looking back, it feels like three weeks have been packed into a week and a half.  I remember when I started the project, I felt awful - I struggled to start, required a ton of guidance, and didn&rsquo;t feel like I understood my code very well.  I felt very defeated during parts of that first week.  Now that we&rsquo;re done, I feel great - the weekend and second week went much more smoothly for me - the logic came a little bit easier, and when, like our warm-up exercises, I got the logic down but had some hiccups with execution, I felt less reserved about asking for help.  I think it has helped to watch our instructors work on warm-up exercises in front of the class and see that they, too, get input from the other instructors.  I guess it&rsquo;s taken the stigma out of it a bit.  The last part of the project, after thinking on it overnight and working for a while, I didn&rsquo;t know how to start, and felt comfortable asking for guidance instead of spinning my wheels and feeling frustrated like I would have before.</p>

<p>I also think back to Passionate Programmer, when Chad talks about how explaining something can help you understand what you&rsquo;re doing on a deeper level than just writing the code.  I also found that to be the case a few times in the second half of this project, when I had completed code and was explaining it to someone else.  I didn&rsquo;t always explain it in the best way that clicked immediately with them, but it felt good to help other people and I really did find I even understood it better myself when I was explaining how and why I had written the code I did.  I also found throughout the project that I liked working in a pair more and more.  I was able to bounce ideas off someone, talk problems out, I was held accountable to explain what I was doing, and I couldn&rsquo;t waste too much time futzing on something I knew I didn&rsquo;t know - it wasn&rsquo;t just my time I was wasting.  It was good to have a second set of hands to help and a second set of eyes to ask &lsquo;why did you do that?  Are you sure you don&rsquo;t need to do this instead?&rsquo;  It also felt great to share in the happiness of completing the project, made that much sweeter by the frustration we shared along the way.</p>

<p>I do wonder if I had to complete the project all over again, if I could without help.  I think at this point I would not be able to do it completely un-aided, but I felt the repetition inherent in this project really helped me, because there were certain things that I did so many times, it sunk in way deeper than if I had only done it once or twice, such as the relationships portion of the project.  I do still think I need practice on the business intelligence-type portion; the way objects interacted in the relationship iteration was pretty straightforward and only took one or two hops between objects.  The business intelligence was a little more complicated - objects got up in each others business, and I think I could learn that component better before moving on.  It was my intention this weekend to go through all of my code to write what each method does to help with this, but it looks like we may be doing that this afternoon in class.</p>

<p>So&hellip; first real project is finished.  Do I feel like a developer?  Answer is still no.  I feel like my confidence went up a bit towards the end of this project, and I&rsquo;m still in awe of how much I&rsquo;ve learned in only one month, but I still had a ton of questions and things I didn&rsquo;t know how to do with this project.  I&rsquo;m still learning how OO programming works and don&rsquo;t have all the concepts down.  It doesn&rsquo;t feel natural to me yet.  I think that&rsquo;s when I&rsquo;ll feel like a developer - when the language feels more natural, and I can start to &lsquo;think in Ruby&rsquo;.  I remember feeling like I was starting to make progress in learning French (before a semester in Japan learning Japanese wiped it all out) when I could think in French, even if basic.  Once I get to that point with programming, I think I&rsquo;ll feel like a developer.  Until then, I&rsquo;m an enthusiastic learner and really excited to get to that day.  I do still feel like I&rsquo;m on the right path though and this program was a good decision for me.  I still get so excited when I figure something out, especially if it&rsquo;s on my own, but even if I need help.  It feels exhilarating to me to look at this project (which I know is small in terms of what we&rsquo;ll be doing later on, but felt pretty monumental in the moment), see it run, and think Yeah, I built that.  There&rsquo;s a certain je ne sais quoi, but I feel a rush when I&rsquo;m writing code and learn something new or figure something out, whether it&rsquo;s a warm-up exercise or a big project like this.  I&rsquo;m still waiting for a lot of &lsquo;a-ha&rsquo; moments, but I think my biggest one so far is how much I like doing this.  I really can&rsquo;t wait til my skill level catches up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sales Engine Week 1 Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/02/sales-engine-week-1-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T09:59:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/02/sales-engine-week-1-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that the first week of Sales Engine is wrapped up, I&rsquo;m feeling in a better place now than the first few days.  Starting out the project by looking over the specs, it was daunting but I kept my stress relatively low by reminding myself that we a) have a week and a half to complete the project and b) will be taking this one little baby step at a time.  I was also excited to try out programming with MiniTest - I knew that forces you to take little bites in your coding.  I worked with my partner, Shane, to map out how the baby steps we&rsquo;d need to take to complete the project in Pivotal Tracker, and was ready to get to work.</p>

<p>Once it came to the actual coding, we didn&rsquo;t get off to a strong start.  The first night of the project, we loaded all the files in their respective classes, but soon found out the next morning we were loading them incorrectly for this project - we were drawing on the type of loading we did in Event Reporter, and for this project, each CSV row needed to be an instance of an object.  Both Shane and I thought we had learned enough from previous projects to get this one started on our own, but we really struggled to get the files loaded properly and relied on a lot of help from classmates and Katrina.</p>

<p>After a day extreme frustration and self-doubt, yesterday we were able to actually make some progress with search capabilities and starting on relationships in search functionality across objects.  At this point we&rsquo;ve relied less on our instructors for input, and have asked small questions of our classmates when needed, but the logic of this part of the project is making sense to me.  I may have some questions on implementation, but logically I feel sound.  Now that I&rsquo;m getting the hang of things, I&rsquo;m also enjoying MiniTest and my rainbow dots of goodness when all my tests pass.  It might take a little longer to code with Minitest, but it&rsquo;s really helpful to make sure your code works straight away and make little tweaks if needed.  I do believe I&rsquo;m being trained Pavlovian style to feel elation when I see rainbow colored dots.</p>

<p>I would have never thought my biggest roadblock would be loading the damned files, but here we are.  It&rsquo;s one of those things that I couldn&rsquo;t formulate on my own, but now that I look at the code, I think I&rsquo;m making sense of it correctly, but I will probably still work on talking through it with some of the more experienced classmates or instructors to make sure I have it down before continuing to our next project.  To me, even if the code is correct, there&rsquo;s no sense in handing in a project with the code unless I understand it, or I&rsquo;m not going to learn anything or progress in upcoming projects.</p>

<p>So far, I feel relatively good about going forward with the relationship portion of the project, and I&rsquo;m hoping that business intelligence is also not much of a logical or logistical roadblock for me.  The biggest thing I want to work on right now is studying up on when I would use certain techniques, because that&rsquo;s still kind of confusing for me - when would I use an instance method or class method?  When is it best to use an instance variable?  Hash versus array?  Once I see someone&rsquo;s code, I can usually make sense of it, but I get tripped up in writing it myself and making the decision to use this over that.  Honestly though, that&rsquo;s the same way I&rsquo;ve been with any language.  When I was learning French or Japanese, I could read it all right, but when it came to speaking it myself, it took a while for actual sentences to come out instead of misplaced or mispronounced words and incorrect grammar.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been an interesting experience working in a pair, too.  I&rsquo;m not sure where I would be with this project if I was working on it independently.  It seems like Shane and I had the same stumbling blocks and for the most part are at the same level with what we&rsquo;re understanding and what&rsquo;s confusing to us.  I know a few of the pairs are groups where one partner is a lot stronger than the other in their current knowledge level and comfort with implementation, but I think Shane and I were pretty well matched.  It is interesting in a pair - I find myself focusing on &lsquo;Am I doing too much of this myself?  Does it seem like I&rsquo;m trying to control our pair, and am I making him feel like he&rsquo;s being cut out?&rsquo;  I think I&rsquo;ve been a little more vocal on when we need help and I&rsquo;m used to managing a team from my previous job, so I&rsquo;m trying not to make it feel like I&rsquo;m managing our team - I want it to be an equal partnership.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t believe we&rsquo;ve only been in gSchool only three weeks - it feels like it&rsquo;s been far longer.  One of the questions to reflect on is whether I feel like a developer yet, and I can&rsquo;t say that I do.  I am still really frustrated that I couldn&rsquo;t start a project like this without significant help, and I feel like I&rsquo;m behind where I should be in class.  I&rsquo;ve been studying independently but everything we&rsquo;re supposed to know hasn&rsquo;t quite clicked yet.  I am hoping that &lsquo;a-ha!&rsquo; moment comes soon, but even once it does, I think I&rsquo;ll still feel like I&rsquo;m learning to become a developer.  Hopefully somewhere down the road in this course I&rsquo;ll feel like I can confidently say I am, and I also realize it&rsquo;s not a function of being &lsquo;done learning&rsquo;.  I&rsquo;ve never met a single developer who hasn&rsquo;t been learning something new or expanding on their knowledge, and I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ll be any different.  So what&rsquo;s the tipping point of knowing enough that I feel like a developer?  I&rsquo;m not sure, but I am looking forward to that point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
