<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-26T23:32:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving On]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/moving-on"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T04:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/moving-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the 7+ years since I&rsquo;ve left college, the longest I&rsquo;ve lived in one apartment is two years; I lived longer in my college apartment.  On Monday I move into my eighth place.  It feels like a lifetime ago I moved into my first place after leaving Michigan, a shared house in Petworth, DC where my room was so tiny I had to push the mattress to the other side of the bed frame to open the drawers of my dresser.  I paid more for that room than I did for my 850 square foot apartment in East Lansing.  I didn&rsquo;t care.  I was so excited to start my life, discover the city, figure out who I was without the crutch and comfort of my friends or my family.  It was a new adventure.</p>

<p>Compared with what we have now, I didn&rsquo;t have a lot back then; a few pieces of furniture, clothes, pots, pans, dishes.  A lot more of my college apartment joined me in DC when Brock and I moved in together six months after the move to DC.  I&rsquo;ve been moving these possessions around with me each move.  I&rsquo;m fairly confident I could guide anyone through reassembling our futon in my sleep.</p>

<p>Inevitably, we acquired new belongings in each new apartment.  Our apartment now includes an impressive variety of furniture from Ikea or Craigslist and years of purchases from Bed Bath and Beyond for each new apartment.  We got a dog a few years in, and I learned one needs a surprising amount of stuff for a 13 pound furball.  New clothes, new books (I&rsquo;m still mad at myself for selling most of my books back in my freshman year of college, and have never gotten rid of a book since), new furniture, new electronics.  We keep moving to bigger places, and always somehow manage to acquire stuff to fill the extra spaces.</p>

<p>And each move, I&rsquo;ve purged things I no longer needed or wanted.  Bags and bags of clothes, a TV, backpacks, houseplants, and lawn furniture are just a snippet of my stuff that&rsquo;s floating around out there somewhere, maybe still being used by their new owners, not to mention the pure junk I just threw away.  On the whole we tend to have more stuff with each move than what we started with, but it helps to keep the growth in check.</p>

<p>But this move feels different from the others.  It somehow feels more consequential than the move from DC to Denver to start a whole new career and leave everything I&rsquo;d built up behind.  As I was packing tonight, I realized that even through seven previous rounds of purges, I&rsquo;d kept a ton of unused things from my college years.  I found a number of shirts and a pair of shoes I&rsquo;d bought to pick up guys in the bars and clubs during my study abroad at Cambridge.  Jewelry from body piercings long healed shut.  Years of accumulation of eye shadow and lipstick even though I haven&rsquo;t even put on mascara in almost two years and hardly wore more than that after graduation.  Perfume from various trips to Europe during high school and college that have been untouched for years.  The University of Cambridge hoodie I was so proud of and couldn&rsquo;t bear to part with over a decade after I said goodbye to Gonville and Caius.</p>

<p>With the exception of one bottle of perfume, it&rsquo;s all gone now.  I don&rsquo;t know if I kept all of it for so long because I had really thought I&rsquo;d use it again, or if it was just a reminder of the life I used to have.  Either way, it&rsquo;s time to let go and move on.</p>

<p>Especially after getting rid of the sentimental remnants that I really only look back on when moving, I&rsquo;m struck by how little I use most of our possessions on a daily basis, and how much less of that I really need to be &lsquo;mine&rsquo;.  As long as I have my clothes, my computer, my toiletries, and my medications, there&rsquo;s not much else I really need that has to be mine.</p>

<p>Maybe it&rsquo;s turning 30 in less than a month and realizing that my window of time for all the adventures I still want to have in life is narrowing, maybe it&rsquo;s realizing my marriage has slowly turned into a friendship that&rsquo;s at a shit or get off the pot moment, maybe it&rsquo;s frustration with where I&rsquo;m mentally, emotionally at right now, but I feel like I&rsquo;m at a turning point.  I&rsquo;m scared shitless not knowing where Brock and I will be six months from now and filled with anxiety that I didn&rsquo;t do enough with my 20s.  It feels like the end of something big, and the beginning of something big; the path just hasn&rsquo;t been fully laid yet.  No matter what happens, I&rsquo;m determined to leave the past in the past, and start this next stage in life as a new adventure I fully intend to make the most of.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Sore Throat Smoothie, Ever]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2014/02/the-best-sore-throat-smoothie-ever"/>
    <updated>2014-02-28T10:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2014/02/the-best-sore-throat-smoothie-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>Ingredients</h5>

<ul>
<li>1 heaping tsp coconut oil*</li>
<li>1 &frac12; tsp protein powder**</li>
<li>1 &frac12; heaping cups frozen fruit</li>
<li>Rice milk</li>
</ul>


<p>Go nuts with what kinds of fruit you want and try different pairings.  Peaches, mangoes, berries, cherries&hellip; it&rsquo;s all good.</p>

<h5>Instructions</h5>

<p>Put coconut oil, protein powder, and fruit in a blender (I prefer to use an immersion blender in a sturdy mixing beaker).  Pour in rice milk until it fills in the cracks between pieces of fruit.  Blend.  Enjoy.</p>

<p>* Just in case I am not the only one who didn&rsquo;t realize what coconut oil was - it&rsquo;s not a liquid, it&rsquo;s a solid.<br>
** I like <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Omega-Nutrition-Pumpkin-Protein-21-Ounce/dp/B004L3VLFK/ref=sr_1_cc_1?s=aps&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1393604845&amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&amp;keywords=pumpkin+protein+powder">this one</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Five Weeks at Table XI]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/10/my-first-five-weeks-at-table-xi"/>
    <updated>2013-10-13T17:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/10/my-first-five-weeks-at-table-xi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&rsquo;m five weeks down at Table XI.  It still boggles my mind that a year ago, switching careers to become a developer wasn&rsquo;t even on my radar yet, and here I am now, shipping a big push to production on my first project at my first programming job.</p>

<p>I started at Table XI on September 9th, and spent my first few days exploring the code base I&rsquo;d be working on and helping to squash stray bugs.  The first few days were pretty stressful - I didn&rsquo;t understand a lot of the code base, and one of the first big bugs I had was in the javascript, which I still don&rsquo;t understand very well.  My mentor had told me my first few days, I&rsquo;d feel like I was in left field but it would pass quickly, but I had a hard time taking it to heart and felt I should be contributing more quickly.  I started to feel better when I talked to other people and heard how long it took them to ramp up when they first start a job - weeks and even months, even if they were experienced developers.</p>

<p>I rounded out the end of my first week attending Windy City Rails.  I&rsquo;d really wanted to go, but thought that since it was my first week, I didn&rsquo;t want to push it asking Table XI if I could take the time off to go.  The day I was moving out of my apartment in Denver, I got an email that they were sending me, so I was really excited.  It ended up being an awesome conference - I met a ton of people from companies around the Chicago area, the greater Midwest, and beyond, and the talks were really interesting.  I was pretty surprised how much I was able to pick up - a few of the talks were over my head, but I was able to take something concrete away from most of them.  It was also great to be able to get to know the Chicago Rails community so soon after moving here - I found it to be a very welcoming community, and I also had the chance to meet with other women in Chicago who had recently graduated from programs similar to gSchool, so it was great to talk to them and share stories.</p>

<p>Week two at Table XI, in addition to squashing bugs, I started to work on my own stories, and even had some deployed to production.  I was still feeling pretty nervous at the beginning of the week, but by week&rsquo;s end, I was starting to build my confidence when I realized that I was able to contribute on my own.  I think the biggest lesson that week for me, though, was not feeling bad about asking questions or being embarrassed about admitting I didn&rsquo;t know how to do something.  As my technical mentor brought up later, I was very honest about my skill level when interviewing, and they knew they were bringing in a junior developer that would require some training - I didn&rsquo;t have to apologize or feel guilty that I didn&rsquo;t know everything from day one.</p>

<p>The company has been great to work for - everyone has been extremely supportive and happy to help in whatever way they can.  I have a technical mentor that I&rsquo;ve been working with closely on my current project, Noel Rappin, and he has been wonderful at explaining complex ideas and answering the million questions I&rsquo;ve had.  I&rsquo;ve become a lot more comfortable asking not just Hey, I don&rsquo;t know how to do this, can you help?, but also Hey, I can get this to work but it&rsquo;s probably not the best way.  Can you show me how you would approach this?  Any other developer at the company that I&rsquo;ve asked for help, regardless of whether they touch my project at all, has been willing to help me out with a question, or even for extended pairing.</p>

<p>I have loved the project manager, Jen Mozen, I&rsquo;ve been working with too.  We work with Pivotal Tracker, and she&rsquo;s awesome at putting in all the information us developers will need, and clarifying any questions we have.  She is amazing at getting to the heart of what a client wants by asking the right questions and knowing their needs, as well as being forthright with what the development team will be able to accomplish in the given time parameters.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also been working closely with Jen during my onboarding process, and I have to say - I&rsquo;ve never worked anywhere with as thorough an onboarding process and as clear a commitment to making sure their employees are happily adjusting to their new job.  The best part of the onboarding process has been the bi-weekly check-ins, as well as this big board of sticky notes where I wrote down what I want to accomplish in the next six months, and Jen did the same for what Table XI would like to see me accomplish in that timeframe.  It runs the gamut from walking the dog ten miles per week to mentoring other developer-in-training students to learning more about application security and performance speed.  In our check-ins we look at my goals, talk about where I am on them,  see what I can do to get to the rest of my goals, and what the company can be doing to help me.  It&rsquo;s very clear they really care about their team, and it&rsquo;s been a good feeling as I settle into my new career.</p>

<p>The past few weeks, I&rsquo;ve continued to work on new stories for my project, and while we&rsquo;ve pushed up to production continuously, the first big feature push that I&rsquo;ve been working on since I started was this past Friday.  It&rsquo;s only been five weeks, but it feels a world different from when I started.  I understand the code base much better, and know the little quirks that run through it and how things interconnect.  I feel better about my skills, and more comfortable with knowing when to look something up on my own versus when to ask for help or to pair up to tackle a problem.  I&rsquo;d love to show you what I worked on, but most of it is on the admin side - trust me though, the code is super sexy (h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/rodchile">Rodrigo Garcia</a>, who taught me code is sexy).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also participated in an inception with a new client, where we worked with the client during an all-day session to understand what the client needs, scope the criteria of the project, draw up some wireframes, and really just start to understand how we can bring the client&rsquo;s vision to life.  One of the reasons I wanted to work with a consultancy was to help code other people&rsquo;s dreams into reality, so it was a great experience to be there at the beginning with someone who will hopefully become a client, and I&rsquo;m really excited about the project.</p>

<p>Overall everyday life at Table XI has been great.  It&rsquo;s a pretty laid back environment, with a lot of perks.  We have an office chef that cooks fantastic meals for lunch every day, there&rsquo;s a company-sponsored Starbucks run every afternoon, there are flexible hours, and an amazing rooftop that&rsquo;s perfect for company-sponsored movies - I caught the last one of this season, Spaceballs.  They are also very committed to being involved with the local community, and are hosting Girl Develop It meetups and supportive of me mentoring Dev Bootcamp students.  Coming up is a dodgeball tournament with other tech companies in Chicago.</p>

<p>So yeah&hellip; that&rsquo;s been my first five weeks in a nutshell.  I&rsquo;m loving developing, and excited about continuing to get better.  It&rsquo;s crazy how much I&rsquo;ve learned in just over a month.  Little lessons of win for me are form objects and the active attr gem, Avdi&rsquo;s naught gem, feeling more confident with Factory Girl and testing in general.  I&rsquo;m still developing a workflow that works best for me and learning how to break complex problems down into small, testable, bite-sized problems that I can tackle with a level head even under time-constraints without stress, but I know that will come with time.  For now, I&rsquo;m loving what I do, and can&rsquo;t wait to see where I am a few more months down the road.</p>

<p>One of my goals for the next six months is updating my blog more regularly, so hopefully you&rsquo;ll be hearing from me more often!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chile. Finally]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/09/chile-finally"/>
    <updated>2013-09-28T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/09/chile-finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before gSchool even started, we found out our friends Sarah and Rod were getting married a few weeks after gSchool graduation.  They live in Santiago, Chile and were getting married down there, so we figured it was the perfect trip to a) see the two of them, since we obviously don&rsquo;t get to see each other very often, and b) take a much needed vacation after six months of non-stop work at gSchool.  Turned out it worked just fine with my eventual job too, since I didn&rsquo;t start until September, and we would be taking off for Chile at the beginning of August.</p>

<p>We flew in to Santiago, and it was really interesting to see the city during our cab ride in.  Like any city, there are upscale areas and less affluent areas, and we saw a lot of everything on our way in.  Besides a lot of houses in the less affluent areas with corrugated roofing, it looked a lot like any American city, except with more graffiti and lots of stray dogs (more on that later).</p>

<p>We ended up staying at a penthouse condo in a really nice area of the city that we found on <a href="http://www.vrbo.com/387159">VRBO</a> that had a great view of the city.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/santiago_view.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>We met up with Sarah, Rod, and her family for dinner that first night and got to see the neighborhood where Sarah and Rod live.  We also had the chance to ride the metro in Santiago - it was the cleanest public transit I&rsquo;ve been on in my life, and super easy to use.</p>

<p>The next day was the wedding, which took place at this adorable little restaurant, bakery, and event space, <a href="http://www.kuchenhaus.cl">Kuchen Haus</a>.  It was a beautiful wedding - the official parts were in Spanish, but the vows were done in Spanish and in English, and it was really beautiful to watch and was such a reminder that love has no boundaries.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/sarah_rod_wedding.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>The reception was so much fun.  Lots to eat and drink, tons of dancing, and we learned that one stereotype at least is true - the Chileans were much, MUCH better dancers than any of us gringos.  I&rsquo;m fairly certain that Rod must be able to dislocate his hips at will, because I&rsquo;m not sure how else he was able to bust out some of those moves.</p>

<p>It was also cool to interact more with Rod&rsquo;s family once everyone had a bit to drink and was less shy about the language divide.  There&rsquo;s also this great tradition at Chilean weddings - people like to party to the wee hours, so in the middle of the night, guests are served chicken soup to give them more energy and strength so they can keep going for a few more hours.</p>

<p>The next day we slept in since we were still pretty jet lagged and recovering from the night before, and then explored the city a bit.  The presidential palace, La Moneda, was all blocked off for renovations, so you really couldn&rsquo;t see much of anything.  The surrounding areas reminded me of DC though - pretty dead since it wasn&rsquo;t a weekday, but filled with a lot of businesses that cater to the proximity to the palace.</p>

<p>We just kind of walk down the main boulevard the palace is on for a few miles, and ran into Cerro Santa Lucia, this little hill in the middle of the city that used to be a military fort, but is now decked out with fountains and really beautiful facades.  It&rsquo;s not a huge hill, but it had a great view of the city at sunset - I was really glad we happened to run across it.  It was one of the most beautiful sights in Santiago.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/cerro_santa_lucia.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>The following day we spent with Sarah&rsquo;s family as well as her other gringo friends from Australia going on a winery tour at <a href="http://www.undurraga.cl/undurraga/?lang=en">Vina Undurraga</a>.  Since it was winter there wasn&rsquo;t anything growing, but we still got the tour of everything and the wine tasting.  More than anything it was just nice to spend a low key day with everyone before people started taking off.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/chile_gang.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>The next day we took one of those open air double decker bus tours of Santiago.  It&rsquo;s the middle of winter there in August, but we lucked out - it was in the 60s for the most part during our trip and sunny almost every day, so it wasn&rsquo;t uncomfortable to spend the whole day outside in just a sweater.  The bus tour was all right, and we got off at certain points to walk around and explore.  Anyone trying to get tourists into their shops or restaurants had a field day harrassing us.  It&rsquo;s pretty damned obvious with my blonde hair I&rsquo;m not from there, so we cut our exploring around the central market a bit short.</p>

<p>We spent the next few days in Valparaiso, Chile with Sarah and Rod, who decided to postpone their honeymoon and didn&rsquo;t mind spending their post-wedding vacation time with us.</p>

<p>Valparaiso is absolutely gorgeous.  Santiago may be the biggest city and the commercial power in Chile, but Valpo has the soul.  It&rsquo;s right on the ocean, and the city is built on huge hills, so the city is full of beautiful views and winding streets.  A lot of the houses are brightly colored, so it&rsquo;s visually stunning to look at.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/valpo.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>Exploring Valpo at night was a lot of fun.  There&rsquo;s little commercial strips tucked here and there in neighborhoods up in the hills, away from the main part of the city closer to the water.  I wish I remembered the name of the restaurant, but we ate dinner our first night at a pizza place, and it was literally the best pizza I&rsquo;ve had in my life.  I say this as someone who has had Chicago pizza from some of the best places now - still doesn&rsquo;t come close to this little place in Valpo.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s interesting in Chile - people tend to eat really late at night, so we ended up taking a nap at 5 or 6 a few days, sleeping a few hours, and then going out to get dinner.  It was actually quite refreshing, and we had a second wind to explore the city a bit and see it in a different way.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/valpo_street.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>One thing about Valpo is there&rsquo;s street art literally everywhere, of all different kinds.  One of the guys in my gSchool class created an app to track street art for his individual project, and he would have had a field day in Valpo.  To me, the street art we saw was a major component in what made the city so charming.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/valpo_street_art.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>We had to see Pablo Neruda&rsquo;s Valparaiso house, La Sebastiana, while we were in Valpo, and it was gorgeous inside and out.  Even if you don&rsquo;t know Neruda&rsquo;s work, see his house if you&rsquo;re ever in Valparaiso - so beautiful and it makes you feel creative and alive just walking through it.  Don&rsquo;t skip the audio tour in English.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/la_sebastiana.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>The most unique form of transport in Valparaiso is the funicular.  Since the city is so hilly (to the point there were a few streets we could not get up in a car with four people plus luggage) and with so many winding streets, they built these little railway elevator things in the late 19th century that are still in use today.  It&rsquo;s a great way to get around, and as for me, I couldn&rsquo;t stop thinking about the Motorcycle Diaries every time I rode in one.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/funicular.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>The rest of our stay in Santiago, we just took in the city.  We visited an old prison in the city that was notorious under Pinochet, that has since been turned into a museum and cultural center, with lots of meeting space for classes and events.  It struck me simultaneously as slightly creepy, but also a way to help the community heal, and turn what was an awful place with deplorable conditions into a place the community can gather to take cooking classes and ballet lessons - it&rsquo;s a way to move on.  We also got to see the college Rod went to, which is absolutely gorgeous, and took a boat tour on the harbor to get some amazing views of the city.</p>

<p>I was really sad to leave Valpo.  The atmosphere is relaxed, the people so nice, the city so beautiful, the food so good - I was tempted to stay there on a permanent vacation, but I&rsquo;ll settle for going back one day for a longer stay.</p>

<p>We spent our last day in Chile with Sarah and Rod in Santiago before heading back to the airport.  We went up to Cerro San Cristobal, this massive hill that&rsquo;s in the middle of the city, for a better view and to take one last look around before we left.  It&rsquo;s beautiful from up there, but it was a bit smoggy that day and my camera isn&rsquo;t that great.  Below is a professional picture of Santiago right after a rain, so the smog was cleared up.  It really is a beautiful city with the Andes in the background.
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/santiago.jpg">
<br><br></p>

<p>And then it was back to the airport, and back to real life :(
<br><br><br>
Just some general thoughts on Chile:</p>

<ul>
<li>So, I mentioned at the beginning of this post the stray dogs.  They are EVERYWHERE in Chile.  At first I didn&rsquo;t get it - there had been a bunch of islands in the Caribbean where there were stray dogs, but it was pretty clear there that people didn&rsquo;t have money to spay or neuter.  Chile is a wealthy country.  The dogs in the islands were also scrawny with obvious health issues.  In Chile, they looked well fed and well taken care of - there were a bunch that even had sweaters on for the winter.  Turns out, it&rsquo;s a cultural thing - from what I was told, Chileans believe it is against God&rsquo;s will to spay or neuter a dog.  They were put on this earth to reproduce, so that&rsquo;s what they&rsquo;re going to let them do.  I saw plenty of people putting food out for the dogs, so at least if people hold this attitude, they&rsquo;re taking care of them.</li>
</ul>


<p>It was really sad for me though, because these were still dogs - they wanted love just as much as my puppy.  They still knew if you looked them in the eye, they might get some food or love out of you, so they&rsquo;d walk over with their ears down and their tail wagging.  I had a really hard time with this, and against everyone&rsquo;s advice, I couldn&rsquo;t help petting the dogs.  Even strays need love.
<br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/street_dog_valpo.jpg">
<br></p>

<ul>
<li><p>People in Chile are super nice.  Everywhere we went, even if people didn&rsquo;t speak English well, they went out of their way to be helpful and kind.  This wasn&rsquo;t just people in the service industry, but people we met everywhere.  I&rsquo;d honestly say it rivaled New Zealand for friendliness.</p></li>
<li><p>The food in Chile is phenomenal.  Everywhere we went, it was fantastic, whether it was Chilean food or ethnic food (who knew Chile had such good Lebanese?).  They love their sandwiches, meat, and seafood, but I think one of the things I enjoyed the most was the most simple - mashed up avocado on toast.</p></li>
<li><p>Chilean drivers are crazy.</p></li>
<li><p>Every time I travel, I can&rsquo;t help but think of stereotypes, and how wrong they tend to be.  On this trip, I thought a lot about the typical American view of all of Latin America as poor, dangerous, and filled with drug smugglers.  Sarah even mentioned a close friend warned her to be careful of the drugs when she moved to Chile.  I can&rsquo;t get over how some Americans don&rsquo;t realize how diverse Latin America is, and differentiate the countries.  Chile is the most advanced, wealthy country in Latin America with a human development index in the same range as the United States.  Seeing different parts of the country, it was hard to think of it as very exotic at times given Santiago especially looked in many neighborhoods like any large city in North America or Europe.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>There were parts of the city that looked pretty rundown, and whenever I visit another country that Americans stereotype as poor, it makes me think Oh, this is what they&rsquo;re thinking of when they visualize this place.  Which then just makes me think of all the parts of America that wealthy Americans are so good at forgetting about, the poor areas that they never see and the people they consciously forget about as much as possible.</p>

<p>Never let a stereotype stop you from traveling somewhere.  Look into it, do your research - chances are your assumptions were incorrect and you&rsquo;d be missing out on an amazing experience.
<br><br></p>

<p>So, to sign off - bye, Rod and Sarah.  We had a great time, and I hope we get to see you again soon!
<br><br>
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/rod_sarah_brock_erin.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Whole Mess of Thank Yous]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/a-whole-mess-of-thank-yous"/>
    <updated>2013-08-18T17:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/a-whole-mess-of-thank-yous</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know this is a little late, but better late than never, right?</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a bunch of people I need to thank for their help in supporting me throughout gSchool.  Without their help, it wouldn&rsquo;t have been as rewarding an experience for me; without some of their help, I wouldn&rsquo;t have been able to do it at all.  A huge thank you to everyone listed here, and to a hundred others who helped me along the way.</p>

<ul>
<li>First off, to <a href="http://twitter.com/verdi_michael">Michael Verdi</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/wengzilla">Ed Weng</a> of LivingSocial, for holding the intro to programming workshop that kicked my entire adventure off.  If it hadn&rsquo;t been for their workshop, I would have never realized a) that I could do this and b) how fulfilling it is.</li>
<li>There were a lot of people who helped me out when I got stressed, but <a href="http://twitter.com/edatrix">Lauren Spath Luhring</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/aimzatron">Aimee Maher</a> were the two people who were there closest to me through the most stressful times and put a smile back on my face.  Thanks, ladies!</li>
<li>All of the other <a href="http://people.jumpstartlab.com">gSchool students</a> deserve a big thanks too.  Everyone brought something valuable to the table, and everyone was so helpful - there was a genuine feeling of teamwork throughout the class, and I never felt like anyone was trying to stand up taller by standing on someone else.  I learned so much from all my classmates and hope I helped them learn, too.</li>
<li>Of course, the fabulous <a href="http://jumpstartlab.com/team">gSchool instructors</a> were, well, fabulous throughout the course.  One of the reasons I chose gSchool was because of the quality of the instructors, and they didn&rsquo;t let me down.  They knew their shit, were great at teaching the full group, and were also great at providing one on one help and advice.  <a href="http://twitter.com/kytrinyx">Katrina</a>, especially, took the time to give me a lot of one on one help and also made sure I knew she believed in me, letting me know what I was doing great at and what I needed to work on.  I really appreciate the time they all put into all of us students.</li>
<li>My first mentor, <a href="http://twitter.com/decoydrone">Jim Denton</a>, was amazing.  He was the one who really pushed me and taught me the value of testing by pointing out all the unnecessary headaches I was causing myself.  I really appreciated all the time he spent with me, sometimes an entire afternoon, whipping me into shape and showing me a new way of thinking.</li>
<li>A huge thank you also to my second mentor, <a href="http://twitter.com/tundal45">Ashish Dixit</a>.  Ashish has had awesome ideas for how to refactor some of my gnarliest code, and also introduced me to Table XI - something I can&rsquo;t thank him for enough.  More than that, he&rsquo;s helped point me in the right direction with my jitters on starting my first programming job, and has offered to continue to be my mentor post-gSchool (which is awesome since we&rsquo;ll both be in Chicago!).  He is amazingly smart, so open to helping, and really excited about the broader Ruby community - I feel so lucky to have been teamed up with him.</li>
<li>More than anyone else though, my biggest thanks go out to my wonderful husband, <a href="http://twitter.com/brock">Brock</a>.  I quite literally could not have done this without his support, and support me he did.  He was so excited for me when I decided I wanted to become a programmer, and didn&rsquo;t mind relocating with me to Denver.  Throughout the course he has done most of the housework and took care of the dog when I was studying all the time and helped me out with programming questions throughout the course whenever he could.  He was also so emotionally supportive when I was frustrated, stressed, and drained, and is relocating with me all over again to Chicago without complaint.  I don&rsquo;t know how I got so lucky to have him.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[gSchool Is Over]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/gschool-is-over"/>
    <updated>2013-08-16T21:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/gschool-is-over</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&rsquo;t been updating this as much as I should be, but wanted to post an update on my last month of gSchool and what&rsquo;s been going on since it&rsquo;s over.</p>

<p>My last month of gSchool was pretty hectic with job searching.  I really wanted to take my time to interview with a variety of companies, and find the place that was the best fit for my top two priorities: firstly, I wanted to find a place that was a good fit for me culturally, where I liked the people I was working with, and looked forward to coming in and working with them every day, and where their values were consistent with my own.  Secondly, it was imperative that I work with a company where I could continue to learn, and that would nurture my ongoing learning process.</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t want to just take the first thing that came along, so I really took the time to get to know a number of companies to find the best one for me.  This meant a lot of phone interviews, skype interviews, in person interviews, and take home coding challenges.  I felt pretty bad, because given how busy I was with the interview process, I wasn&rsquo;t able to put in the time that I wanted to on my group projects.  Everyone understood though; everyone else was doing the same.</p>

<p>At the end of it, I came away with three job offers from wonderful companies, any of which I could see myself enjoying culturally, and where I would learn a ton from awesome co-workers and interesting projects.  It was especially difficult as the offers were all from my top three cities - Chicago, Portland, and Denver.  In the end, I decided to accept the offer as a software developer with <a href="http://www.tablexi.com">Table XI</a> in Chicago, for a few reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>I love Chicago.  It&rsquo;s an amazing city, with a ton to do.  I&rsquo;ve always considered myself a city person, and I am really excited to get back to a large city with a ton of cultural options, great public transit, people from all over the world - all in America&rsquo;s third largest city.  It helps a lot too that even though it&rsquo;s a huge city, it&rsquo;s still the Midwest, so people are incredibly nice there.  Also the cost of living, especially compared to DC, is great.  Also I have a bunch of friends from college there.  Also the food there is incredible.  Really, just a lot of alsos.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m back within driving distance of my family, which I haven&rsquo;t been since college.  Speaking of college, I&rsquo;m also within driving distance of East Lansing, so I can go back home and catch some Spartan football and basketball games!  Go Green!</li>
<li>Most importantly, I felt that Table XI was the very best fit for me personally.  There are so many things that I love about them, and throughout the interview process, there were a hundred little moments where I just knew this was where I was supposed to be.  The people are all amazingly smart, excited about the work they&rsquo;re doing, happy to help, and yet humble and super nice.  It&rsquo;s a consultancy, so there&rsquo;s a bunch of different projects they get to work on.  They do a lot of work with community groups and non-profits, which is a great fit for my social relations background - even though I&rsquo;m not saving the world full time anymore, it&rsquo;s still one of my values.  The people stay there long term because they genuinely love working there.  There&rsquo;s about ten more pages worth of things I could say about how great Table XI is, but long story short - I&rsquo;m unbelievably excited to start working there and am so thankful I have this opportunity.</li>
</ul>


<p>The actual end of gSchool has been bittersweet.  On one hand, I&rsquo;m happy the madness is over and excited to be moving on to my new job, but on the other, I really miss working with all my classmates - they were amazing people and I made some good friends there.  We had a big party the last day, both at Galvanize and later on at Chris&rsquo;s house, and it was so good to let everything out and spend one last (quite memorable) night with everyone, but I also realized this is likely the last time we were all going to be together.</p>

<p>Since gSchool ended, it&rsquo;s still been a whirlwind.  We started looking into relocating to Chicago, I flew out to Chicago to find an apartment (success!  We&rsquo;ll be living in West Lakeview), we visited our friends in Chile (separate post forthcoming), and now I&rsquo;m trying to cram in all the Denver things I didn&rsquo;t have time to do during gSchool, and meeting up with all my friends here one last time before I leave.  On top of that, I need to pick my sister&rsquo;s New Leaf Massage site back up, and have some books I want to read before starting with Table XI, so this is definitely not a lazy vacation for me!  I did get some reprieve on New Leaf though - my sister just found out she&rsquo;s relocating to Phoenix for her husband&rsquo;s job, and it takes about six months to get set up as a massage therapist in the state, so I&rsquo;m hoping to have everything ready to go by that time.</p>

<p>So - crazy and exciting times, and I&rsquo;m looking forward to this next chapter!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Individual Project Wrap Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/06/individual-project-wrap-up"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T10:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/06/individual-project-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s difficult to describe this as the &lsquo;wrap-up&rsquo; to my project, because there is still a ton of work that I am going to do to it.  I have a pretty massive list at home of all the things I&rsquo;m planning on tweaking, adding, removing, optimizing, addressing - ALL THE INGs.  Still, at the end of the formal project portion of this undertaking, I&rsquo;m pretty proud of my work.  There&rsquo;s things I&rsquo;d do differently and a lot I want to make better, but I am really proud that I was able to do this on my own (with some help from instructors and Brock, especially for the Javascript portion) given I&rsquo;ve only been developing for four and a half months.</p>

<p>I knew this project was going to be tough, and the two toughest things for me were dealing with the Javascript, and correctly figuring out the logic for the open time slots on any given day for a given appointment duration the client was requesting.  If the time slots were all one hour long and started on the hour, it would have been easy peasy, but the appointments could be 60 or 90 minutes, and started every half hour.  The final code needs refactoring, but I tested the shit out of it with a context for every contingency of appointment variation, so I know the logic is sound even if the code needs clean up.  This will be especially helpful when I work on Meghan&rsquo;s final site - she actually has appointment times ranging from 30 to 90 minutes with 15 minute increments, and her hours vary by day, with a few days having large gaps in the afternoon.  Now that I know what I&rsquo;m doing, I&rsquo;m confident I&rsquo;ll be able to make these changes for the final product.</p>

<p>One thing I am wondering how to do is make the calendar more flexible.  Right now, I have the days she&rsquo;s off completely blocked out of the calendar; if she decides to open on a random Saturday, I&rsquo;d like for her to be able to do this without me touching the Javascript that controls which days are blocked out in the calendar.  This is something I&rsquo;d like to talk to my mentor about going forward, but it&rsquo;s an interesting problem to solve and I&rsquo;m excited about it.</p>

<p>It was also really cool to see Meghan&rsquo;s reaction when I showed her the final first version of her site.  She was really excited and loves it, which is good since this is the first, first, baby step skeleton version of what her site will eventually be able to do and how it will look - for final roll out, I&rsquo;m planning on engaging the services of Kyle for a few hours to get the design looking good.  I realize my design skills are not very good right now, and I want to give her an actual professional product.</p>

<p>All in all, I&rsquo;m proud of the work I&rsquo;ve done, both with the site and in general with everything I&rsquo;ve learned in the past few months.  There&rsquo;s still a ton to learn and to do with Meghan&rsquo;s site, but this was a solid first iteration and really helped me to realize my own skills as a developer.</p>

<p>Her site can be seen here: <a href="http://www.newleafmassage.net">newleafmassage.net</a></p>

<p>Look for exciting updates once gSchool is complete and I have the time to finish this up!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Individual Project Midway]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/individual-project-midway"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T11:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/individual-project-midway</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My feelings upon starting the individual project were a mixture of excitement and nervousness, weighted towards the former.  It was scary to think though - I was hoping through this project, I&rsquo;d realize I know more than I think I do, but was nervous the opposite would turn out to be true.  I can happily report that, so far, I&rsquo;m feeling my knowledge is right about where I thought it was.  I&rsquo;m not the world&rsquo;s greatest gift to programming, but I&rsquo;m certainly not awful either.</p>

<p>So far, it&rsquo;s been a little bit slow.  I&rsquo;ve managed to get to the point where an admin can sign in, search for a client, and create an appointment for the client.  Once the appointment is created, they get a text via Twilio.  This sounds like a lot, but was actually really simple, and I&rsquo;m working on the hard part now - the logic for time slots and determining which time slots are taken, which are free, and which of the free ones have enough time in them to schedule appointments (if it&rsquo;s a thirty minute timeslot, nothing can be scheduled; if it&rsquo;s a sixty minute timeslot, only the sixty minute massage should show up as an option).</p>

<p>I think once this part is complete, the rest of the MVP will fall into place pretty easily - this is what most of the difficult logic rests upon in the app.  I owe Katrina a huge shout out for her help yesterday.  She helped me to think through how to structure this logic (we have a DayPlanner class, a TimeSlot class, and a Clock class - the last one is because we don&rsquo;t care about the date for a timeslot or dayplanner; only the time), and it would have been a lot messier without her guidance.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also really wanting to use AJAX for some of the implementation on the front end.  I&rsquo;d love for the admin appointment scheduling to be on one page - admin searches for a client; once client is selected, the date picker pops up; once date is selected, time picker pops up; once time is selected, massage duration selection pops up with appropriate options given the duration of the available time slot.  I really don&rsquo;t know how to do this, so I&rsquo;m hoping I can get some help from my new mentor.</p>

<p>Speaking of which, I&rsquo;m really excited to be working with Ashish - just from our email conversations so far, he seems awesome.  We&rsquo;re doing a get to know you call on Sunday, so I&rsquo;ll find out more then, but I&rsquo;m excited.</p>

<p>I also am really grateful for the help Jim gave me in the previous mentoring rotation.  He was really great to work with and provided me with great feedback when I was starting to go down paths that didn&rsquo;t make a whole lot of sense in my code.</p>

<p>It is crazy to think there&rsquo;s only seven weeks left.  This has felt like a really long four plus months so far, and at times when the stress level was off the charts it felt like the end of the program was eons away.  Now that I&rsquo;m nearing the end, it&rsquo;s a weird feeling.  I&rsquo;m excited with everything I&rsquo;ve learned so far, and excited to start a new job, but it just feels kind of weird that we&rsquo;re already almost done not that we&rsquo;re at the end.</p>

<p>It is an interesting thing to look back though at where I was a few months ago.  Coming in, I had no clue what I was doing, and for the longest time didn&rsquo;t feel like a real developer.  Now, I&rsquo;m beginning to feel like I can say with confidence that yes, I am a developer.  I can take a problem, and find a way to implement a real solution.  I still have a lot to learn with new styles and refactoring and need help from teammates, mentors, or instructors, but that&rsquo;s not really any different from where most real developers are in real life - most developers work on teams and get advice and feedback from others too.</p>

<p>I still do have to pinch myself to think how far I&rsquo;ve come in just 18 weeks though - this feeling is incredible and I&rsquo;m so glad I made the leap to restart my life as a developer.  It hasn&rsquo;t been easy by any means, but it&rsquo;s sure been rewarding and I can&rsquo;t wait to see what I&rsquo;ll be doing next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feed Engine Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/feed-engine-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-05-24T15:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/feed-engine-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ah - FeedEngine is in the books.  For some reason, this was a difficult project to get through, even though I loved what we were building.  It seems like we&rsquo;ve reached a point in the class where a lot of people are feeling burned out, and I think that impacted some of our team this project - we ended up dropping a lot of the functionality that I wanted to implement because we couldn&rsquo;t get through it all with the amount of work the group as a whole was putting in.</p>

<p>At the same time, I learned a lot from this project.  The two things I&rsquo;m happiest learning about are how to interact with external APIs (Kyle and I implemented the Instagram service, and I implemented the Foursquare service), and refactoring my code to extract logic from the views and controllers, and even the model.  For this, I have to thank Raphael.</p>

<p>An example of refactoring can be seen in our implementation of the logic relating to the user show page.  For this page, we needed to break a user&rsquo;s trips out into current trips, past trips, and upcoming trips, AND we needed to determine whether the trip was private AND we needed to determine, if the trip was private, if the current viewer was authorized to view the trip.  Sounds easy, right?  I really wasn&rsquo;t expecting it to be that horribly difficult, but it ended up being harder than I thought to implement all of this logic in one place.</p>

<p>The way I originally wrote this part of the code, I had current, past, and upcoming trips in the Trip model, and handled the logic for whether the current user could view each trip in the controller.  Raph put a stop to that.  We ended up extracting all of this logic into a UserShow class, which took in the current user and the user whose profile was being viewed, ran through each trip to see if it was private and if the current user had viewing rights, and then split the trips into their correct timeframe.  You can view the final implementation here: <a href="https://github.com/raphweiner/feed_engine/blob/master/app/lib/user_show.rb">github.com/raphweiner/feed_engine/blob/master/app/lib/user_show.rb</a></p>

<p>I also learned to place even more value on communicating with your team, especially when you&rsquo;re touching someone else&rsquo;s code.  There were a number of times that I pulled down master to build on code I had previously implemented, and found it had been refactored so much that I had to spend half an hour just figuring out what the heck it was now doing.  Worse, there were times files I had been working on were deleted or the refactoring broke the code I had originally written.  This was pretty frustrating for me, and I&rsquo;m even more aware now that if you&rsquo;re touching someone else&rsquo;s code, it&rsquo;s a great idea to work with them first.</p>

<p>Overall, I think our project is a good first step, but I wish it went further.  There&rsquo;s a lot more functionality I would like to build out and changes I&rsquo;d like to made to the front end to make it look sleeker as well.  I&rsquo;d link to the project, but Jeff is turning off the extra background workers he had provisioned, so the app will no longer work.  I&rsquo;m taking some time off between graduating gSchool and starting a job, so one thing I&rsquo;d love to do is to keep working on Kreepr and get it to a place I&rsquo;m happier with, with more features, more security and background logic, and a cleaner look.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also really excited to be starting our independent project next week.  I don&rsquo;t have 100% sign off yet, but I had talked to Katrina about my idea, and it sounds like I&rsquo;ll be able to do PART of it - my original idea is too large a project to do independently in 9 days.  What I&rsquo;m going to be doing is making a website for my sister, who is a massage therapist.  Once it&rsquo;s completely done, I&rsquo;d like to have functionality to let Meghan set her schedule with a base weekly schedule that autogenerates up to two months out, with the ability to go in and tweak individual days.  In addition to a confirmation e-mail when an appointment is scheduled and a reminder e-mail a day or two out, I&rsquo;d also like to implement text messaging a few hours before an appointment to remind the customer, and let them text back if they need to cancel the appointment.  I&rsquo;d like to integrate with Yelp to show her overall review count, and maybe recent reviews.  Lastly, I&rsquo;d like the ability to allow customers to pre-pay for individual massages or massage packages online, and allow Meghan to charge a cancellation fee for missed appointments.</p>

<p>One of the requirements for this project is to build an API and gem on our own, which I think fits in nicely with the scheduling component.  There are a few other gems out there that I found, but none of them have been maintained in the past year; I&rsquo;d also love if my gem would give back to the community so that other people can use it for their own projects as well.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really excited to be doing this project, for a few reasons.</p>

<ol>
<li>I think the building out the scheduling component will be a pretty difficult, and it&rsquo;s a challenge that I think will be extremely rewarding.</li>
<li>I really want to give this gift to my sister.  Not only is she basically one of the most wonderful, caring, compassionate people on the planet and I want to help her grow her business, she also hooks me up with free massages.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m really glad to be doing this project while I&rsquo;m in gSchool.  Since this is a site that will actually be used, security is a big concern and I want to be sure that everything is locked down.  It will be really good to have that second set of eyes from my instructors so they can let me know if there are any vulnerabilities that I overlooked.</li>
</ol>


<p>So, super excited to get cracking on that, but also, not going to lie - I&rsquo;m excited about the long weekend too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boulder Startup Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/boulder-startup-week"/>
    <updated>2013-05-17T15:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/boulder-startup-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday we took a group trip up to Boulder to participate in Boulder Startup Week, and even though it meant sacrificing a work day which we really need for our project, I&rsquo;m so glad we went.  I met a ton of really awesome people, got to take a look around some really interesting companies, and saw a new side of Boulder that I hadn&rsquo;t explored yet.</p>

<p>We started the day with a visit to the Boulder office of LivingSocial, which is composed only of LS developers.  It was really interesting to go back though - even though it&rsquo;s so different from the DC office, it still had that LS feel - the funky furniture converted into conference tables, the white chairs with the weird arm rests that never stayed in place.  I talked to two guys who worked there, one who worked on front end for user acquisition, and one who worked on back end for the LS Amazon partnership, and it was really interesting to see what they were working on, especially since I still recognized a lot of it.  We then went to QuickLeft to talk to some people on the team there and take a look around the offices, which were also really cool - especially the herb garden they have growing in the landscaping right next to the kitchen!</p>

<p>After that I met up with my friend Lauren, who still works at LivingSocial in Seattle, who was a fly-in for startup week, Ashe Dryden, and my husband Brock for lunch, and we were joined by my instructor Franklin.  I&rsquo;ve followed Ashe on Twitter for a long time, and it was really great to meet her in person finally, and seeing Lauren again (I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;d seen her since last September) was awesome.</p>

<p>After lunch we participated in the startup crawl and visited a bunch of different startups in the Pearl Street area.  There were so many amazing people we met, and I was really excited at how friendly and welcoming the whole community was, both the employees at the startups, and the other crawlers we met along the way.  There&rsquo;s so many people doing such diverse things, but everyone we met was really passionate about their work and the value they&rsquo;re bringing to their customers/clients.  I&rsquo;m so happy to be in this space; I feel like so many jobs are just that - just a job.  In the Ruby world, there&rsquo;s so much exciting stuff going on, and this really seems to be a community driven by passion.</p>

<p>I went to a Women in Tech dinner with Ashe, Lauren, and a few other people, and then we were off to Pivotal Labs for the Boulder Ruby Meetup.  Again, a ton of really engaging and passionate people there.  It&rsquo;s also really neat to have been to enough meetups at this point that I tend to see a lot of familiar faces and people to catch up with, and also meet new friends.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really excited to be a part of this community and to be joining it as an employee soon.  I can&rsquo;t believe we&rsquo;re down to 9 weeks left in gSchool - it&rsquo;ll be over so soon!  I&rsquo;m really excited to see what I&rsquo;ll be doing next, but it looks like there&rsquo;s lots of interesting options out there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Personal TDD Challenge]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/my-personal-tdd-challenge"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T20:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/my-personal-tdd-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m not the happiest with middleman and want to address a few challenges, so I&rsquo;m creating a blog from scratch with Rails, hopefully without needing to reference the Blogger tutorial at all.</p>

<p>My challenges:</p>

<ol>
<li>Create an attractive design to practice front end development and showcase a blog I can be proud to show off - I really don&rsquo;t like the current look of my blog, and especially as I&rsquo;m increasingly going to be showing it off to potential employers, I need to stand behind and be proud of my work.</li>
<li>Practice my Rails skills from soup to nuts.  I love working on teams, but it necessitates touching only part of the code.  This will be good practice for me to make sure I understand the process beginning to end, and it&rsquo;s great practice before our individual project in two weeks!</li>
<li>Most importantly, 100% of the code will be written in TDD.  Literally not one line of code will be written without a failing test.  I haven&rsquo;t always been the best about adhering to strict TDD, and I need to get better - I know firsthand why it&rsquo;s important, and no skill is going to magically appear; I need to practice it.</li>
</ol>


<p>So&hellip; wish me luck!  Hopefully you&rsquo;ll see a finished product I&rsquo;m proud to stand by in no time :)  The biggest challenge I&rsquo;m anticipating is just finding time to work on it with all the other projects I&rsquo;m working on, but honestly, since there&rsquo;s no firm deadline and I am going at my own pace, working on it so far has almost felt like a break from everything else.  It is a good feeling - programming can be tough, but even just the small amount of time I&rsquo;ve put in so far reminds me of how much I love to do it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feed Engine Week 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/feed-engine-week-1"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T12:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/05/feed-engine-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The thing I&rsquo;m most excited about with my FeedEngine project is that once it&rsquo;s finished, I&rsquo;ll actually want to use it.  We&rsquo;re building a group travel blog that lets you integrate the Twitter, Instagram, and Foursquare activities for all travelers within a trip.  I really love to travel and usually am pretty poor about documenting my travels aside from taking pictures and posting them to Facebook when I get home, so this is a product I will actually use.  I&rsquo;m sure other people who want to document a group trip in this way would like to use it as well - although to be honest, I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s a bad product for just a solo trip either.</p>

<p>One thing I am going to be cautious on with this project is that from everyone I talked to at Hungry Academy, this was their hardest project.  We have three weeks to get it done, but I&rsquo;m conscious of how quickly that due date catches up to you.  One thing my team is doing is that we have some ideas in the back of our mind of functionality we would like to create, but we&rsquo;re not going to start building it at all until the base functionality is completed and we&rsquo;re sure we have the time to put into the extra features before the project is due - we&rsquo;re full assing a small set of features instead of half assing a large set.</p>

<p>For this project, I&rsquo;m working with another team member on the front end.  So far, I really haven&rsquo;t enjoyed working on the front end in projects - it feels tedious and mind numbing to me, so I&rsquo;ve tended to work on the back end, which I strongly prefer.  I&rsquo;m trying to take myself out of my comfort zone a little so that I can learn more of the front end, try to use some of the jQuery I learned, and just get the basics down.  As much as I really don&rsquo;t want a job focusing on front end development, the reality is that most jobs will touch it to some degree, and I want to know the basics for when that does happen.  I also feel pretty lucky in that this is part of the project I will probably be able to work with Brock on when I get stuck - we&rsquo;re far enough in Rails that he has no idea what&rsquo;s going on, so I haven&rsquo;t been able to work with him on questions, and that&rsquo;s one of the things I miss from when we were just learning Ruby.  It was fun to sit down and pair/troubleshoot with him, and I should be able to do that with him with the front end.  On the other hand, I&rsquo;m hoping to finish up the nuts and bolts of the front end so that I can do some of the back end code for this project as well.</p>

<p>Another thing that&rsquo;s on the back of my mind as we head nearer and nearer to graduation is finding a job once gSchool is complete.  If possible, I&rsquo;d really like to stick around in Denver; if I can&rsquo;t find anything here, Portland is at the top of my list.  Aside from geography, I&rsquo;m simultaneously nervous and excited about finding a company that&rsquo;s a good fit for me.  When looking at a company, one of the things that will be at the top of my list is finding a company that values ongoing learning for their newer hires.  I have learned so much in this program and still have 10 weeks left, but I know that I&rsquo;ll still have so much to learn and fine tune when I&rsquo;m done, and I want to be in an atmosphere that is understanding of that.  Also, just at a base level, I want to work with people I get along with and that communicate well.  I&rsquo;ve been in jobs where everyone gets in, puts their head down, no one talks to each other, and then you go home - that&rsquo;s a really awful environment.  I think there&rsquo;s a stereotype that that&rsquo;s what programmers do, but so far I&rsquo;ve found it to be completely untrue.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m hoping to work at a company that has a decent sized dev team - I&rsquo;m not yet comfortable enough in my skills that I feel ready to work at a small startup where I&rsquo;m one of two or three people writing code.  I&rsquo;d also really like to find a place that&rsquo;s laid back, where there is opportunity to move up with the company and work on more complex projects as my skills improve, and lets me draw on the soft skills I&rsquo;ve built up from my previous life before I started gSchool.  It&rsquo;s not the number one focus of mine, but I also am looking at a decent compensation package commensurate with my skills and the previous experience I bring with me.</p>

<p>From talking with others in the program, I think we&rsquo;re all a little nervous and very excited to see where we all end up in three months.  At the end of the day, I&rsquo;m going to value my intuition - when I interviewed with LivingSocial, I knew it was the right job for me at the time when my face hurt from smiling after I left the interview.  I can&rsquo;t put my finger on it, but it&rsquo;s this electric feeling where things just feel like they&rsquo;re the missing puzzle piece - that&rsquo;s what I want.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Son of Store Engine Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/son-of-store-engine-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-04-19T16:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/son-of-store-engine-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Son of Store Engine was an interesting project for me.  I started off feeling a little shaky on my Rails knowledge versus Store Engine, and I still feel like I have a ton to learn, but towards the end of the project I felt like the struggle I put in started to pay off.  In the beginning of the project, I began to realize I wasn&rsquo;t ever really sure how my params were being passed back and forth, what the heck was in my session, how I could get information from point A to point B, and by the end, I felt like I understood these things better.  A huge part of this process was the better errors gem and information contained there by default, and in the live shell.  It was enormously helpful to be able to inspect params, what was in my session, and be able to play around in the live shell to manipulate this information to output what I needed.  We had used better errors in Store Engine, but I felt like I didn&rsquo;t know how to harness it&rsquo;s power to my advantage until the latter part of this project.</p>

<p>I also got the chance to put processor controllers and models into play for information that we wanted to render on one page, but involved four different forms and databases.  This was something I attempted to do last project and failed pretty miserably, but I had really wanted to try this project.  It took a little wrangling to get it, but I think the final result was pretty clean code and I&rsquo;m so glad I know how to do this now.  Here&rsquo;s a snippet:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>class Checkout
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  def initialize(params)
</span><span class='line'>    @guest = Customer.find_by_email(params[:guest][:email])
</span><span class='line'>    @guest ||= Customer.create(params[:guest])
</span><span class='line'>    @shipping = params[:shipping_address]
</span><span class='line'>    @billing = params[:billing_address]
</span><span class='line'>    @credit_card = params[:credit_card]
</span><span class='line'>  end
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  def shipping
</span><span class='line'>    new_shipping = ShippingAddress.new(@shipping)
</span><span class='line'>    new_shipping.customer_id = @guest.id
</span><span class='line'>    new_shipping.save
</span><span class='line'>    new_shipping
</span><span class='line'>  end
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  def billing
</span><span class='line'>    new_billing = BillingAddress.new(@billing)
</span><span class='line'>    new_billing.customer_id = @guest.id
</span><span class='line'>    new_billing.save
</span><span class='line'>    new_billing
</span><span class='line'>  end
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  def credit_card
</span><span class='line'>    new_credit_card = CreditCard.new(@credit_card)
</span><span class='line'>    new_credit_card.customer_id = @guest.id
</span><span class='line'>    new_credit_card.save
</span><span class='line'>    new_credit_card
</span><span class='line'>  end
</span><span class='line'>end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Overall, I think our project wasn&rsquo;t great (there&rsquo;s a lot more I would have liked to do with a few extra days), but I think it was pretty good.  The final result is here: <a href="http://pink-sose.herokuapp.com/">pink-sose.herokuapp.com</a></p>

<p>It also feels weird to be at the halfway point of gSchool.  It feels like ages ago we were doing logic problems for warmups and getting stressed over Event Manager.  At the same time, it went by quickly with all we&rsquo;ve been doing, and I&rsquo;m hoping that July 19th comes as quickly as well.  My big hope for the second half of the program is that I can manage the stress a little better, and maximize my learning with the time I&rsquo;m putting in.  I&rsquo;ve been putting in about 12 to 14 hours a day during the weekdays on average, and 8 to 12 on weekends when we&rsquo;re working on a project.  At the same time, I feel like there&rsquo;s still so much that we&rsquo;re exposed to that I&rsquo;m not learning as well as I&rsquo;d like, and the physical exhaustion and frustration over all the things I haven&rsquo;t been able to pick up yet are taking their toll.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Son of Store Engine Midway Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/son-of-store-engine-midway-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T10:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/son-of-store-engine-midway-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been quite the week.  We started Son of Store Engine, which takes code from our last project and adds on to it - but we can&rsquo;t sacrifice any of the functionality from the last project in reworking the code.  I am happy that we have a project like this and not everything is built from scratch.  The reality is that most everyone will be working with legacy code when we&rsquo;re done, and this is really good practice for me.  So far, I&rsquo;ve found it to be harder than building something from scratch in a lot of respects; I first have to understand what the code is doing (some of it is written in a style I&rsquo;m not used to).  Then, there have been a few times I&rsquo;ve built on top of something or tweaked something seemingly insignificant, and previous functionality has broken, so it&rsquo;s an extremely valuable lesson.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been really different in this project for me versus most other projects I&rsquo;ve worked on, at least so far.  Most of my last projects (Traffic Spy maybe excepted), I&rsquo;ve felt like I&rsquo;ve contributed a good percentage of the code base and functionality.  This project, what I&rsquo;ve worked on so far, it has felt like I haven&rsquo;t written as much code or functionality as I&rsquo;d like; it&rsquo;s been a tedious process for a lot of the functionality so far.  I&rsquo;m hoping that it speeds up some from here, but I will also try to keep in mind what Chad Fowler mentioned in our talk with him today - when working with legacy code, a lot of it can be tedious, and that&rsquo;s just how it is.  I&rsquo;m hoping I can also learn some common things to look for so I don&rsquo;t get so hung up spending time on what should be small fixes.  For example, I struggled for about an hour yesterday wondering why the functionality I wrote to remove a line item from a cart when the quantity was set to zero wasn&rsquo;t working.  Turns out quantity was being stored as a string and not an integer.  On the plus side, it felt damn good once I got that fix working!</p>

<p>On the last project, I felt relatively confident with Rails (although I still asked Kareem for help a good amount of times when I got stuck, which he was happy to provide), but I actually feel less confident with this project.  I think there&rsquo;s just more we&rsquo;re delving into with this project and I&rsquo;m picking this up more slowly.  One thing I really have enjoyed is since I have a lot more questions this time that can&rsquo;t really be answered within the team, I&rsquo;ve been reaching out more to &lsquo;real&rsquo; developers for an answer, and I&rsquo;ve found that in answering my question, they&rsquo;ve also taught me other things that I didn&rsquo;t even realize I didn&rsquo;t yet know.  I had what I thought was a quick question for Horace from LivingSocial last night, and in answering it, he taught me about custom routes for controllers beyond the 7 verbs, which actually fascinated me way more than my question.  I&rsquo;m also really looking forward to mastering the art of using a processor class so that I can have forms for multiple databases on one page; I tried that in my last project but we could only get the functionality working halfway, so we had to rip it out and never had time to implement it properly.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also really looking forward to working with my mentor.  My first mentor had to back out do to time constraints, but I&rsquo;m set to work with my new mentor, Jim Denton, on Monday after class.  Jim works at Groupon, and I&rsquo;ve worked with him before to address questions as they&rsquo;ve come up in projects.  He&rsquo;s been super helpful when I&rsquo;ve worked with him in the past, so I&rsquo;m looking forward to working with him as a mentee.  I have a lot of general questions I want to ask (like the processor class), but it will also be really helpful to be able to bounce project ideas off of him and hopefully come up with solutions to problems I don&rsquo;t even know I have yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Store Engine Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/store-engine-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-04-05T15:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/store-engine-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By far, Store Engine has been the most exciting project I&rsquo;ve worked on.  It was awesome to be able to show my friends and my family an actual site that I&rsquo;d built - somehow showing them all the awesome output from a command line just doesn&rsquo;t have the same pizzazz.  Not that I didn&rsquo;t work hard on my other projects too, but I felt like I pushed myself even harder for this project and poured myself into it very aggressively.  The final product is something I&rsquo;m really proud of and I think my team made a great effort.  It really meant a lot too that we were chosen to present our project as a group demo.  It felt so good that not only did we come together and learn a ton, feel like we could all feed proud of our finished product, but that other people recognized the hard work we put in, too.</p>

<p>Having worked on a real Rails project, I think I&rsquo;m ready to make some changes to the next project I have.  First off, while we started off thinking of what a customer would need to do and thought of the pages we would need, I think we got off track from there.  Next time, I&rsquo;d really like to focus on the customer experience and let that drive the development kind of from the outside in, and try to do TDD that starts with feature testing and flows down to the model testing instead of building up the model and working to feature testing.  I also am still getting a hang of how to most effectively use MVC to the fullest and most elegant extend - I feel like I was doing a lot of work in the view or controller.  I know that&rsquo;s not the best way to do things, but any time I tried to refactor everything blew up - of course most of what needed the most refactoring was what was built in the last few days of the project, so unfortunately I didn&rsquo;t have a lot of time to spend on it since we had to push to get the project completed.  For my next project I want to start out learning how to better assign the heavy lifting to the model and have it output correctly to the view instead of doing that work elsewhere.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also appreciating more than ever how awesome it is to try &lsquo;stretch work&rsquo; - there were a few times during the project that I tried to tackle something that was a bit out of reach of what I already knew how to do, instead of just sticking to the easy stuff that I had already done.  Some of the time I gave it my all and tried to find answers on my own, and when I couldn&rsquo;t my more knowledgeable teammate was more than happy to step in and help me to find a solution, but I appreciated the patience the group had to let me try to find a solution.  When I was able to find a solution on my own, it wasn&rsquo;t always the best code, but it got the job done, and that&rsquo;s what learning to refactor is for!</p>

<p>I think it will depend on the makeup of our next group, but I&rsquo;d like to look into different ways of making sure everyone has a good handle on how the code works without necessarily doing everything as a big group.  Given our group makeup this time, I think that was the best way forward, but I think you can split off into pairs working on different parts of a project without sacrificing knowledge of your code base.  Given how we approached the makeup of our group, I don&rsquo;t think we were actually a lot more productive than a pair of programmers would be.  We may have picked up maybe 25% extra efficiency, but we didn&rsquo;t double our output with double the programmers involved.</p>

<p>All in all, this week was exhilarating.  Our team came together and really hammered through the home stretch of our project, and I have done more outside of class to try to connect with the community.  I went to the Women Who Code event on Wednesday and met some really cool people, some newbies like myself and some women who have been in the industry for years.  It was also great to meet people at the Thoughtbot Drinkup - I finally feel like I have enough of a handle on programming that I can carry on a real conversation, whereas just a few weeks ago everything still had a tendency to feel like Greek to me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also been thinking a lot lately on what I can do to get other women from non-tech backgrounds interested in programming.  I&rsquo;d like to volunteer for RailsBridge and talked to Desi of DevChix about that.  I wonder what else I can do to reach out to women who are intimidated by programming or think they can&rsquo;t do it - obviously the women at RailsBridge have committed to dipping their toes in the water, but I want to reach out to people who are at the place I was at a year go, when I thought my brain &lsquo;didn&rsquo;t work like that&rsquo; and that I&rsquo;d be really out of place with my background.  I&rsquo;m not sure what the best way to do that is, other than evangelizing to my friends and writing about my experience, and keeping an open door to other women who have questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Make Me Think Reading Group 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/dont-make-me-think-reading-group-1"/>
    <updated>2013-04-01T13:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/04/dont-make-me-think-reading-group-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was interesting to read Don&rsquo;t Make Me Think - the examples could at times be pretty outdated, but the ideas behind all of the examples were still very relevant for today.  More so than even 10 years ago, people have an unbelieveably short attention span, and you really need to give a user instant gratification in your site or you will lose them.</p>

<p>(As a side note - It was also really entertaining to me to look at the examples and to remember how professional websites looked 10 years ago and laugh.  Granted, in my last job, we looked at a lot of websites from small businesses that were god awful and violated every principle in this book, but 10 years ago that was the case even for large companies.)</p>

<p>One of the ideas that really clicked with me is how users actually use the web versus what we might like to imagine - I thought it was spot on.  When I&rsquo;m on a site, I hardly ever look at the entire thing, just what I&rsquo;m specifically visiting the site to look for; once I&rsquo;ve found it, that&rsquo;s the end of the road.  This makes it even more important that users need to be able to navigate your site quickly, so intelligible design and naming conventions are key.  Part of keeping everything easy to navigate definitely includes cutting out words - they clutter the page and can make it harder to find what you&rsquo;re looking for.  Lots of text is also pretty easy to ignore - I sometimes find myself getting an error message on a site, and realizing I didn&rsquo;t read the text, precisely because it usually is so easy to ignore.</p>

<p>I also know it violates every rule of DRY, but from a user perspective, it&rsquo;s sometimes good to get to the same destination in three different ways (especially if a site does not have a search functionality).  Take Krug&rsquo;s chainsaw example - why not put that in multiple categories if it&rsquo;s reasonable that a user might look in those categories?</p>

<p>I think the lessons from this book tie in well to our Store Engine project.  We had consciously decided to make our site very clean looking with a lot of whitespace, so that the information on the site really stands out.  There&rsquo;s also very easy links throughout the site to different parts of the site, and an easy flow through to checkout.  To give credit where it&rsquo;s due, we did use bootstrap to help us, so a lot of the thought into the design happened before we touched it, but I think these are still really good principles to keep in mind, even if you are using pre-defined templates, to make sure they are still fulfilling your users&#8217; needs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Store Engine Midpoint Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/store-engine-midpoint-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T10:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/store-engine-midpoint-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think this week has been most interesting from the perspective of learning to work with others in new ways.  Both from the perspective of the increased emphasis on pairing and the larger groups, I feel I&rsquo;ve learned a lot.</p>

<p>To start, I&rsquo;ve gotten a lot out of the structured pairing we&rsquo;ve done.  I&rsquo;ve done pairing before, but the more structured environment is making me a better pair programmer.  If it&rsquo;s not structured, I feel like it&rsquo;s easy for one person or the other to take over, and not really do pairing.  The modified ping pong pairing has been good.  It&rsquo;s also been helpful to look at how other groups are approaching the questions of Store Engine, and take some of their awesome ideas or lessons they have learned, and incorporate them into our project.  The one trap that was easy to fall into though is discussing the project and talking about Well my group did this, and not doing enough coding, which I&rsquo;d like to avoid next time.  It&rsquo;s definitely helpful to have that conversation and I learned a ton, but I would really like to work on my core skills of coding in a pair.  I think it might almost be more helpful to not work on our actual projects but a dummy project; this way you avoid long discussions of project organization or implementation, and you&rsquo;re also not caught in an awkward point of your project that&rsquo;s difficult for someone who hasn&rsquo;t been working on it to jump into.</p>

<p>Working in a group of four has been a lot different from working in a pair for this project as well.  I knew the organization was going to be a little different and we&rsquo;d really have to make sure our communication was open to avoid duplicative work or systems that didn&rsquo;t interact together in the correct way, but it&rsquo;s also more of a challenge with project vision and meshing personalities as well - I hadn&rsquo;t really taken into account how difficult that aspect might be.  I definitely think we ended the week on a smoother note than we started it; I think after some team discussions everyone has a better appreciation that we are coming in with different skills and experience, but we&rsquo;re all a team and no one person makes decisions for everyone.  There&rsquo;s also been a deeper appreciation for, when there is a conflict in a direction we should go, having a respectful discussion of why we should go in a given direction, and coming to a consensus that way.  It might have been a little bumpy at first, but I think it&rsquo;s benefitted all of us - we&rsquo;re going to be in contact with a lot of different personalities and need to work in groups throughout our career, so it&rsquo;s great to learn how to work through that to deliver a quality project that everyone understands now.</p>

<p>In that vein, I&rsquo;ve really liked our group&rsquo;s vision from the get go that even if we&rsquo;re working more slowly than other groups, we&rsquo;re not moving on til everyone understands what&rsquo;s going on.  This has meant that we&rsquo;ve had several coding sessions where all four of us are in a conference room, hooked up to a TV.  Without question this has slowed the project down, but I would prefer that to having two people in the group not understand how a shopping cart is built and how the code works.  I don&rsquo;t know how feasible that is in the working world, but as we&rsquo;re learning, I think it&rsquo;s benefitted the group.  This seems like it&rsquo;s the trickiest part of the project though, and with this out of the way, I&rsquo;m thinking this weekend and next week we&rsquo;ll be able to get a lot of code out in pairs.</p>

<p>We still have a lot to do, but I think at the end of the day we&rsquo;ll deliver a quality project.  I&rsquo;m really excited to see this all come together and to celebrate as a team.</p>

<p>So far, Rails has been interesting.  I&rsquo;m getting over my initial shock of how much it does for you on the back end, but I still feel like we&rsquo;re not done getting acquainted.  There&rsquo;s still a lot of code I look into, and I ask Wait, where is that method coming from?, to find out Oh, that&rsquo;s a Rails thing.  So there&rsquo;s still a lot to learn, but I like the structured nature of REST, and I&rsquo;m really enjoying learning the Capybara testing.  My big complaint is that I don&rsquo;t think (correct me if I&rsquo;m wrong) there is rspec pride for Rails.  Somehow testing is just plain better when you see those fabulous little rainbow dots.</p>

<p>I also wonder how much my feelings will change when we get into the relational component of our project and the different roles of admin, regular user, and unregistered guest.  Stay tuned, but I&rsquo;m hoping this won&rsquo;t be too terrible in terms of either understanding it or implementing it.  The addition to our team of someone who is experienced with Rails and knows how the parts work has definitely been helpful though when there are questions; no one can ever say they didn&rsquo;t get a thorough explanation.</p>

<p>The biggest thing I&rsquo;m trying to absorb is how all everything works so I can extract it to different contexts.  The first few Ruby projects we worked on, I felt like I understood how everything worked in the confines of the project, but trying to apply that knowledge to something new just didn&rsquo;t translate well, which to me says I didn&rsquo;t really learn it fully.  I really want to build an amazing site for my sister, whether it&rsquo;s a project I can work on for school or something I do afterwards, and of course I want to have a firm grasp on what I&rsquo;m doing when I am employed afterward, so I&rsquo;m trying to focus on that when I&rsquo;m learning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[gSchool Two Month Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/gschool-two-month-retrospective"/>
    <updated>2013-03-22T10:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/gschool-two-month-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was the first time I was introduced to Rails with the Blogger project.  Having programmed in Ruby so far, it was very different to me, especially with respect to how much Rails automatically does for you.  It makes it really helpful that you&rsquo;re not writing a ton of finder methods, joining tables, or having to define a create method, but at the same time the level to which Rails is hands off feels really foreign to me still.  I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll feel more acquainted in no time (Ruby felt the same way at first).  It also felt really weird how little &lsquo;classical&rsquo; Ruby we wrote for blogger, and how empty the models were.  Before I started this project, not knowing Rails, I couldn&rsquo;t understand how people could even attempt to be a Rails developer without knowing Ruby, but now I can see why someone might think they could hack it (although I would not recommend it).</p>

<p>It was also interesting to look at the difference between Sinatra and Rails.  In Sinatra, I felt like it was a good middle ground between Ruby and Rails - you still had a lot of responsibility in your hands and were still writing a ton of &lsquo;classical&rsquo; Ruby very manually.  All in all, even though it might feel more comfortable right now, I think I would stick with learning more Rails.  Rails takes a lot of the work out of your hands, and it especially sounds like security is built in to Rails in a way that doesn&rsquo;t come close in Sinatra.  I also really want to become better acquainted with MVC and RESTful development in Rails, so I probably won&rsquo;t use Sinatra much - I don&rsquo;t want anything to get muddled in my mind right now.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t believe we&rsquo;re one-third of the way through class already.  It simultaneously feels like we&rsquo;ve been here for a really long time, but that really long time has flown by in the blink of an eye.  I&rsquo;m still amazed at how much I&rsquo;ve learned in just two months, and I really am excited to see what we&rsquo;ll be doing in the next four.  I remember thinking a month ago Oh god, what am I going to do for my midway project??  I don&rsquo;t know enough to do that!  I&rsquo;m beginning to feel more confidence in myself and my abilities, and now seeing all that&rsquo;s possible in Rails, I think I&rsquo;ll be able to come up with something interesting.  My first thought is making a website for my sister - she&rsquo;s a recently licensed massage therapist and always gives me free massages; I&rsquo;d love to pay her back by building her a site to help her grow her business.  I don&rsquo;t know if I&rsquo;ll be skilled enough by then (I think so), but I&rsquo;d love to build her a site that at least has a booking portion and a blog portion, and maybe an option to pre-pay for massages or packages.</p>

<p>So, the oft-asked question.  Do I feel like a developer yet?  Almost.  Kind of.  I feel like once I get through this Store Engine project, I will feel a lot closer.  I want to make sure I really do understand Rails once I don&rsquo;t have a tutorial prompting me every step of the way.  I also really want to get better at CSS and basic design - I understand what&rsquo;s going on when I read the HTML &amp; CSS book and try simple exercises on my own, but when I try to put that together in, for example, this blog, it kind of falls apart.  I think part of my respecting the Friday this week will be taking in a Railscast on Bootstrap.  But I do feel like once I have the basics on Rails and design down, I will feel like a very junior junior-level developer.  There&rsquo;s still so much to learn during gSchool (and beyond!), but I&rsquo;ll have some core skills to draw on, and a concrete site I can show to people.  Now am I ready for the big time, jumping in to help build something, say, for a thoughtbot client?  No, but I&rsquo;m getting there!</p>

<p>Speaking of thoughtbot, that was one of the highlights of my week.  It was really interesting to hear Ben talk about working with clients, how they approach projects, an the structure and approach of their organization.  I&rsquo;m still not sure what exactly I&rsquo;d like to do when I graduate, but the consultancy business sounds pretty interesting.  You get to work on a bunch of different projects for a short to medium period of time, and you get to interact with the clients (which I suppose can be a blessing or a curse, depending on the client).  This is something I was interested in when I started gSchool - a lot of tech people are really bad at explaining things to non-tech people, and I&rsquo;d love to be a part of bridging that gap.</p>

<p>I was also really interested in learning more about the apprenticeship program in Stockholm.  I would love to get a full time job out of gSchool, but if for some reason I feel like I&rsquo;d like to continue my formal learning for a little longer or I&rsquo;m not finding something as quickly as I&rsquo;d like, I would love to look into apprenticing at thoughtbot.  Thoughtbot sounds like a wonderful environment with really passionate programmers, and Stockholm would be wonderful - it&rsquo;s always been my long term goal to hone my skills, get experience under my belt, and try to find a job in Europe somewhere down the road; maybe this could just accelerate that plan!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML & CSS Reading Group 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/html-and-css-reading-group-2"/>
    <updated>2013-03-18T16:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/html-and-css-reading-group-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was really interesting for me to read the CSS portion of this book - I&rsquo;ve never had any experience with CSS before, and it&rsquo;s interesting to see all the design elements you can implement with pure CSS alone.</p>

<p>I tried to experiment a bit with updating my blog, but had limited success - I think part of it was that the layouts were written in haml, not HTML, which I would have found really helpful in modifying, saying, a .panel class.</p>

<p>Most of what I did (I had previously already tweaked the colors of my blog) was with trying to manipulate the title bar a bit.  I&rsquo;m still not super happy with it, but I can fiddle around with it later.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what it was:
  <img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/ss1.png" /></p>

<p>And here&rsquo;s what it is now:
  <img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ebdrummond.com/images/ss2.png" /></p>

<p>with code:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'>h2 {
</span><span class='line'>  font-size: 40px;
</span><span class='line'>  letter-spacing: 0.06em;
</span><span class='line'>  word-spacing: 0.06em;
</span><span class='line'>  text-shadow: -1px 1px 10px #704111;
</span><span class='line'>}
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Again, really not to happy with it, but more to come soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[gSchool Focus Week Reflection]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/gschool-focus-week-reflection"/>
    <updated>2013-03-15T10:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/03/gschool-focus-week-reflection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed this focus week and the chance to catch my breath and review what I&rsquo;ve learned so far.  I started the week, quite frankly, pretty surprised with the group I was in - I thought for sure I would be in the refresher group, but I was placed in the intermediate group, where we worked on re-doing Sales Engine in the context of a web app.  It was honestly really helpful for me to be able to re-do an old project with the knowledge that I now have.  When I first did Sales Engine, it was a struggle for me, the code I wrote felt very awkward, and some of what Jeff/Raphael helped us with for code creation and refactoring was still really fuzzy in my mind.  This go around, I felt more confident I understood the concepts, and the code felt a lot more natural to me.  I also focused much more intensively on testing, which I think helped to instill confidence in my code as I was writing it, and helped me to catch bugs early on.</p>

<p>In fact, I made a really dumb mistake in my code - to create new object instances between classes, I used each instead of collect, which gave me all the information I needed&hellip; as hashes, not as objects.  I noticed my code wasn&rsquo;t working the way I wanted it to, and quickly discovered it was broken, leading me to (with Laura&rsquo;s help) find my mistake.  If I hadn&rsquo;t been testing as intensively as I was, I don&rsquo;t know that I would have found it as quickly.</p>

<p>Even though the focus week is formally over, I&rsquo;m not done with this project and I&rsquo;d like to keep working on it, if for nothing else than to prove to myself that I can do this.  I know I&rsquo;ve really struggled with self-confidence during this course so far, but I feel like I&rsquo;m turning a corner and the ability to keep up with this project relatively well has been a big boost for me.  That, and when I have a problem I can&rsquo;t work out or a project that&rsquo;s not complete, my brain doesn&rsquo;t want to let it go.  I want to keep working on it til it&rsquo;s done and I can see everything working.  I still feel a kind of rush when I see my code working, similar to that first tingling I felt all the way back at LivingSocial when I went to the intro to programming workshop.  While I do sometimes still feel some anxiety that I&rsquo;m not learning quickly enough, I still really like what I&rsquo;m doing.  I can&rsquo;t wait to see what I can do once this program is over.  I never would have thought I&rsquo;d have learned all that I know now in such a short period of time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve just scratched the surface on this, but I&rsquo;m really interested in learning more about controllers and the MVC model.  I understand as a concept what the controller does, but I&rsquo;m still not clear on how to execute everything in my code.  For this project, for example, where do I validate that a link someone has requested exists?  In the controller, in the router?  I have been trying to finish up the business intelligence component since I still want to become more confident in objects interacting, but once that piece is complete I&rsquo;d like to play around with the controller model Jeff showed us and see if I can figure out some answers.</p>

<p>One area I still feel shaky on is starting a project.  For this one, I was really glad Jeff started it with us, and helped to guide us in the right direction.  Even though I knew Sales Engine at this point and what it did, starting out on my own would have been difficult.  If there&rsquo;s one thing at the top of my agenda going forward, it&rsquo;s to get better at deconstructing spec requirements better so that I don&rsquo;t feel quite so overwhelmed and have a clear idea on how/where to start a new project.</p>

<p>Overall, I&rsquo;m really glad that the calendar was modified for this focus week.  It was really helpful to me and to a lot of other people I&rsquo;ve talked to.  I don&rsquo;t know if it&rsquo;s feasible, but I&rsquo;d love to have another one later on in the course if we reach another point where a lot of people are feeling really behind&hellip; although I hope this week has helped enough so that we don&rsquo;t feel as behind anymore!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
