<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Restart | ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/blog/tags/restart/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-29T21:24:50-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parting Ways]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2015/03/parting-ways"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T20:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2015/03/parting-ways</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve wanted to get this out in some way or another for a while, but wasn&rsquo;t really sure the best way to go about doing so. Now that I&rsquo;m at the point where I&rsquo;m moving again (per usual), I figure it&rsquo;s time to get this out in the open so I don&rsquo;t get weird looks and make people feel awkward when they ask a question and find out what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<p>Brock and I are divorcing. (Phew - there, it&rsquo;s out.)</p>

<p>When I&rsquo;ve told people this, I&rsquo;ve gotten a few common questions, so for the sake of not having to retell the same story 100 times, I figure I&rsquo;d answer some of the questions here.</p>

<p><strong> Q: What??! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Yep. Not an early April Fool&rsquo;s joke, I promise.</p>

<p><strong> Q: But I just saw you guys { insert your not so long ago time here } ago and you seemed great! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Well, that&rsquo;s not really a question (cheater), but I&rsquo;m sure we did seem fine. Things haven&rsquo;t been going well for quite some time, but through all of it we were still friends so I&rsquo;m sure we looked like we were enjoying each others&#8217; company; we probably were. But I guess that was part and parcel of the problem - we&rsquo;d become just friends.</p>

<p><strong> Q: I&rsquo;m so sorry! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Again, not a question. But don&rsquo;t be sorry - while the fact our relationship went this way sucks, I&rsquo;ve been happier in the past few months than I&rsquo;ve been in years. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ve felt this alive since I first moved to DC almost eight years ago. I haven&rsquo;t talked to him too often in the past few months, but Brock seems to be happier now than he had been as well.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Wait, so what&rsquo;s going on with you two now? Are you living apart? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> We started a trial separation last fall and spent the first two months with zero contact to give ourselves space to recenter ourselves and figure out what we individually wanted. Brock moved out of the coach house, and I stayed there with Lola May and got a roommate. After our two months of no contact was up, we met in person at our therapist&rsquo;s place and talked about what we wanted and where to go from there. It was very emotional to see each other again, and there was some back and forth over email for the next few weeks over whether to give it another go or to move towards divorce. Long story short, we both realized we were holding on to a fantasy of what we wanted us to be, and when we looked at reality, we realized it just wasn&rsquo;t working and it was time to let go.</p>

<p><strong> Q: How did this happen? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Lots of little things gradually added up, and we both have thoughts about different factors that caused this. I&rsquo;m not going to go into specifics, but for me a big part of it was that at a certain point I began to feel the distance growing between us, which over time kicked off a depressive episode. The distance made the depression worse, which widened the distance; they just fed off each other in a downward spiral, with a bunch of little things on top of it.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Well, he&rsquo;s an asshole if he&rsquo;s throwing in the towel! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> I know people mean well and are trying to root for me or cheer me up by vilifying Brock, but it seriously doesn&rsquo;t help and is not reflective of reality; in fact we&rsquo;ve joked that in some ways this process would have been easier if the other person was a piece of shit because it would be much more black and white. Did Brock do things that were shitty during our marriage? Yep, he sure did. But guess what - so did I. Neither of us did anything to purposefully hurt the other person or tried to be a dick. There weren&rsquo;t any affairs or abuse or anything like that. We had garden variety moments of shittiness, but we were both doing the best we could with the tools and resources we had at the time. The decision to divorce is a conclusion we both came to independently at our own pace; neither one of us is abandoning the other.</p>

<p><strong> Q: But why aren&rsquo;t you two working through it? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Like I said, things had been bad for a while, and we had been in couples therapy for about a year. It wasn&rsquo;t getting any better, both of us felt pretty beat down from trying so long to make it work, and we were at the point where I think we would have permanently damaged the prospect of continuing a friendship if we had gone on much longer. Now that we&rsquo;ve had plenty of time apart (we&rsquo;ve only seen each other in person four times since we separated), I can see quite a few reasons why I don&rsquo;t think we would have worked in the long run no matter what. I&rsquo;m not going to hash that out here, but I will say this whole process has hammered on home how much you&rsquo;re fucking over your relationship and yourself if you don&rsquo;t communicate openly and honestly. You can&rsquo;t hide from your emotions or unpleasant situations - they will come up eventually, and the longer you ignore them, the harder it will be to deal with when they do come to the surface.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Wow. This must be terrible to go through. </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Not something I&rsquo;d love to do every weekend, but it hasn&rsquo;t been so bad, all things considered. There were some patches that were incredibly rough emotionally, especially towards the beginning, but the past few months I&rsquo;ve found peace and acceptance. We talked through a rough draft of the divorce agreement over a nice bottle of cider, and there aren&rsquo;t really any points of contention. We don&rsquo;t own property, never shared bank accounts or credit cards, don&rsquo;t have kids to worry about, so knock on wood, this should not be a very difficult divorce process legally, considering what we&rsquo;ve seen other people go through. We&rsquo;re even on the same page about custody of the dog.</p>

<p>We also still care about each other very deeply as friends and we both want each other to be happy. Neither one of us is out for blood, and we&rsquo;d like to remain friends. This also makes things easier for you, as you don&rsquo;t have to feel pressured to choose a side.</p>

<p><strong> Q: So when is the actual divorce happening? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> After I move and get settled in, I&rsquo;ll be starting the legal process.</p>

<p><strong> Q: How the hell are you so zen about this? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Lots of therapy, lots of self-reflection, lots of time spent with amazingly supportive friends and family, and lots of hard work in working through the issues I brought to the relationship. Not going to lie - there have been times it&rsquo;s been extremely painful, but I&rsquo;ve uncovered and am working through hurts that I&rsquo;ve been carrying around since way before Brock. Like I said before, emotions that you&rsquo;re trying to hide or have repressed will come up eventually, but meeting them head on and working towards a resolution feels pretty damned fantastic.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Do you regret getting married then? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Absolutely not. While we didn&rsquo;t end up working out as a married couple, we shared many wonderful times together and made a ton of memories that mean a lot to me. I&rsquo;m incredibly thankful for everything Brock has brought to my life and for the time we shared together - he wasn&rsquo;t just a husband, but a best friend. I have learned so much through this whole process, both the marriage and the divorce, and it&rsquo;s made me a better person. Besides, I follow the philosophy that I would never go back and change my past, even the painful parts or things I&rsquo;ve done that I&rsquo;m not so proud of - I wouldn&rsquo;t be who I am and where I am today without everything I&rsquo;ve been through. And for the first time in a long time, I can say I&rsquo;m really rather happy with who and where I am.</p>

<p><strong> Q: So what are you going to do now? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Hit restart - it really is never too late.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
