<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Restart | ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/blog/tags/restart/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-26T23:52:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unpacking Memories]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2015/04/unpacking-memories"/>
    <updated>2015-04-26T14:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2015/04/unpacking-memories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just went through my 13th move in the past 12 years, in my 4th city. At a certain point in there, moving got to feeling pretty routine. Some moves were harder than others, especially when I was moving between cities and leaving behind friends and the sense of belonging I&rsquo;d built up, but I can&rsquo;t remember a move I&rsquo;ve taken before that has brought up so many different emotions and memories.</p>

<p>The closest thing to it was when I moved from DC to Denver. I was leaving behind five and a half years in the city I had moved to right after college where I had met my husband and a fucking amazing circle of friends, started my career, and had some of the most memorable experiences of my life. It felt like I&rsquo;d fit so much living into, when you really look at it, a relatively short period of time and even though I knew it was time to move on, it was still hard as hell. There was a last minute change of plans when I left - a family friend died a few days before Brock and I were set to move, so I had to leave in the middle of packing up our apartment to fly back to Michigan for the funeral, and then meet Brock in Denver. I remember starting to cry while I was hugging Brock goodbye in our apartment, getting into an Uber, and totally losing it before we&rsquo;d even hit the first major avenue on our way to the airport. Seeing the city go by one last time while it was still my city and remembering all the things I&rsquo;d done over the years, thinking about everything I was leaving behind, was so painful. I was excited to start a new career in Denver, and the self-importance and pretentiousness that&rsquo;s prevalent in DC had been wearing on me for a while, but I was going to miss the life I had built up. And yet I knew even then that Brock and I had already begun our slow drift apart; I was leaving DC alone more than just physically. I remember hoping the fresh start in Denver would help us get closer again.</p>

<p>As strong as my emotions were during that move, the sheer number of different emotions I&rsquo;ve felt during this move has been staggering in comparison. I am still kind of in awe of the array of feelings it&rsquo;s possible to experience simultaneously. I&rsquo;m still at the point in the divorce process where I&rsquo;m spending a lot of time in self-reflection and working out who I am and who I want to be and how I want to move on with life. It seems like every few weeks I have a new light go off and some insight makes a few more things click into place about what makes me tick. My feelings continuously grow more nuanced, but at any given time I can usually pinpoint upwards of half a dozen emotions I&rsquo;m feeling, sometimes contradictory.</p>

<p>Luckily by the time it came to start packing up in the coach house, I was already well into the acceptance stage of grieving the end of the marriage. For my previous eight moves I had had Brock by my side; even for the moves that happened after things went sour for us, he was still there and it was comforting to feel him next to me. I&rsquo;ve found I&rsquo;m adjusting well to being on my own, but I cannot imagine what moving and confronting all those old memories that is always an inevitable byproduct would have felt like if I was still cycling through the earlier stages of grief.</p>

<p>But one thing I hadn&rsquo;t expected was to have so many memories of the past come up for me once I was here in the new place. I&rsquo;d already come face to face with old memories, both of the good times and the not so good times, when I had been packing up. Of course I still think of everything that happened as I move on, but especially since the move it&rsquo;s just felt like time to focus more on where I&rsquo;m at now and what&rsquo;s in front of me rather than continue to focus on unpacking the past. The first few weeks in the new place fit with that pretty well - it felt really freeing to live on my own again, I liked making the new apartment feel like home to me, and it was great to explore Andersonville and get the first taste of my new life; it somehow hadn&rsquo;t felt like a new life while I was still in the coach house - there were too many memories and too much constraint living in an uncomfortable roommate situation.</p>

<p>But as I&rsquo;ve unpacked there&rsquo;s been a few random things I&rsquo;ve come across that have brought up all sorts of memories and feelings I hadn&rsquo;t been expecting. I thought I had sorted through most of my belongings pretty well while packing up in the old place, but there were still things that I&rsquo;d thrown into boxes without really going through that I have come across here.</p>

<p>This afternoon I came across a set of purple sheets that I bought when I moved to DC. These sheets have been through the wringer and it shows - you could almost read a newspaper through them. After Brock and I moved in together and upgraded to a queen bed, everyone who visited us and slept on our futon used those sheets. And maybe it&rsquo;s weird, but when I found them, all I could think about was all those visits from friends. And then I thought about all those people who were Brock&rsquo;s friends that I would likely never see again. And then I thought about one of my closest friends, Heather, who had taken the rest of the bedding I&rsquo;d had to go along with the purple sheets and how she&rsquo;d moved back to Australia years ago and how our friendship had changed, but I was still hoping to visit her this fall in Hungary where she&rsquo;ll be moving, and how the last time I saw her after not seeing her for years it didn&rsquo;t feel like years had passed and things just slipped into place, and how I hoped that&rsquo;s how it will be with Brock when we go for long stretches without seeing each other. All from some raggedy purple sheets.</p>

<p>And last week while I was unpacking the stuff that had been in my files I found a love note Brock wrote to me from before we got married. It was one sentence long and wouldn&rsquo;t look at all profound if anyone else had happened across it; hell, I&rsquo;m certain I hadn&rsquo;t thought of it as profound when I originally got it. But it was from back before we realized how different our needs were when a sweet little note on <a href="http://waitbutwhy.com/2014/02/pick-life-partner-part-2.html">some random Wednesday</a> was still a thing. At this point I&rsquo;ve become pretty comfortable experiencing unexpected emotions. It doesn&rsquo;t happen with much frequency like it did in the first few months of our separation, but every once in a while there&rsquo;s still a real zinger that comes up and forces me to sit down and just take some time in earnest to think and feel and process. It&rsquo;s hard to look at that note - not some grandiose profession of love tied to a holiday or special occasion, but a simple statement from someone going about his everyday routine who wanted to take a few seconds to let his partner know he was thinking about her and loved her - and not feel a sense of loss.</p>

<p>I think that&rsquo;s what we&rsquo;re all looking for when you really get to the heart of it - not the fairytale of monthly romantic vacations to exotic destinations and non-stop excitement and candle-lit dinners followed by mind-blowing sex every night. At least for me, if processing the divorce has given me any insight as to what I really want, it&rsquo;s that I want to be with someone that I can share 20,000 ordinary days with, and day 13,387 into that, I still want to want to take a few seconds out of my day to let him know I&rsquo;m thinking about him and I love him. No weekly treatises on how much he means to me - he&rsquo;d already know. It&rsquo;s the little things. And the more I look back on Brock and me, the more I see that was never really possible for us for a lifetime. When you get to the root of our individual natures, I need emotional intimacy and a close connection with a partner; Brock needs emotional independence and more distance. We were never going to be able to give each other what we really needed.</p>

<p>So I guess that&rsquo;s the heart of the bittersweetness and tenderness I feel when I look back at my time with Brock. For a time, before we&rsquo;d really had a chance to experience life and what it really means to spend thousands of ordinary days together, we both thought we had the connection we needed. Missing what I felt when I thought that&rsquo;s what we had, that&rsquo;s a part of what I felt when I came across his note. Knowing that despite Brock being a wonderful person that I connected with in so many ways, I&rsquo;d never be able to give him what he needed and he&rsquo;d never be able to give me what I needed - that also contributed to the sense of loss I felt.</p>

<p>I was never naive enough to think that all you need is love. If I&rsquo;d fallen head over heels for a deeply religious social conservative who wanted to settle down in the suburbs and have half a dozen kids, it wouldn&rsquo;t matter how much I loved him - it would be a complete non-starter for me. But when I met Brock and we clicked so quickly and we shared so many core beliefs and values, I thought that all that along with love was all we needed. And if core beliefs and values, love, and effort to make it all work were all you needed, we&rsquo;d be happy together for the rest of our lives.</p>

<p>At least I know better now, and more importantly, I know myself better. I&rsquo;ve unpacked a whole hell of a lot the past few months, and as time has gone on, I find I&rsquo;m able to reflect on my marriage and the past few years of my life while looking to the future, and with a sense of peace rather than pain. But it seems that even as I move forward, there will still be unexpected things I find every now and again that will bring up old memories and, if I&rsquo;m lucky, deeper understandings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parting Ways]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2015/03/parting-ways"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T20:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2015/03/parting-ways</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve wanted to get this out in some way or another for a while, but wasn&rsquo;t really sure the best way to go about doing so. Now that I&rsquo;m at the point where I&rsquo;m moving again (per usual), I figure it&rsquo;s time to get this out in the open so I don&rsquo;t get weird looks and make people feel awkward when they ask a question and find out what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<p>Brock and I are divorcing. (Phew - there, it&rsquo;s out.)</p>

<p>When I&rsquo;ve told people this, I&rsquo;ve gotten a few common questions, so for the sake of not having to retell the same story 100 times, I figure I&rsquo;d answer some of the questions here.</p>

<p><strong> Q: What??! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Yep. Not an early April Fool&rsquo;s joke, I promise.</p>

<p><strong> Q: But I just saw you guys { insert your not so long ago time here } ago and you seemed great! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Well, that&rsquo;s not really a question (cheater), but I&rsquo;m sure we did seem fine. Things haven&rsquo;t been going well for quite some time, but through all of it we were still friends so I&rsquo;m sure we looked like we were enjoying each others&#8217; company; we probably were. But I guess that was part and parcel of the problem - we&rsquo;d become just friends.</p>

<p><strong> Q: I&rsquo;m so sorry! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Again, not a question. But don&rsquo;t be sorry - while the fact our relationship went this way sucks, I&rsquo;ve been happier in the past few months than I&rsquo;ve been in years. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ve felt this alive since I first moved to DC almost eight years ago. I haven&rsquo;t talked to him too often in the past few months, but Brock seems to be happier now than he had been as well.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Wait, so what&rsquo;s going on with you two now? Are you living apart? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> We started a trial separation last fall and spent the first two months with zero contact to give ourselves space to recenter ourselves and figure out what we individually wanted. Brock moved out of the coach house, and I stayed there with Lola May and got a roommate. After our two months of no contact was up, we met in person at our therapist&rsquo;s place and talked about what we wanted and where to go from there. It was very emotional to see each other again, and there was some back and forth over email for the next few weeks over whether to give it another go or to move towards divorce. Long story short, we both realized we were holding on to a fantasy of what we wanted us to be, and when we looked at reality, we realized it just wasn&rsquo;t working and it was time to let go.</p>

<p><strong> Q: How did this happen? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Lots of little things gradually added up, and we both have thoughts about different factors that caused this. I&rsquo;m not going to go into specifics, but for me a big part of it was that at a certain point I began to feel the distance growing between us, which over time kicked off a depressive episode. The distance made the depression worse, which widened the distance; they just fed off each other in a downward spiral, with a bunch of little things on top of it.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Well, he&rsquo;s an asshole if he&rsquo;s throwing in the towel! </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> I know people mean well and are trying to root for me or cheer me up by vilifying Brock, but it seriously doesn&rsquo;t help and is not reflective of reality; in fact we&rsquo;ve joked that in some ways this process would have been easier if the other person was a piece of shit because it would be much more black and white. Did Brock do things that were shitty during our marriage? Yep, he sure did. But guess what - so did I. Neither of us did anything to purposefully hurt the other person or tried to be a dick. There weren&rsquo;t any affairs or abuse or anything like that. We had garden variety moments of shittiness, but we were both doing the best we could with the tools and resources we had at the time. The decision to divorce is a conclusion we both came to independently at our own pace; neither one of us is abandoning the other.</p>

<p><strong> Q: But why aren&rsquo;t you two working through it? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Like I said, things had been bad for a while, and we had been in couples therapy for about a year. It wasn&rsquo;t getting any better, both of us felt pretty beat down from trying so long to make it work, and we were at the point where I think we would have permanently damaged the prospect of continuing a friendship if we had gone on much longer. Now that we&rsquo;ve had plenty of time apart (we&rsquo;ve only seen each other in person four times since we separated), I can see quite a few reasons why I don&rsquo;t think we would have worked in the long run no matter what. I&rsquo;m not going to hash that out here, but I will say this whole process has hammered on home how much you&rsquo;re fucking over your relationship and yourself if you don&rsquo;t communicate openly and honestly. You can&rsquo;t hide from your emotions or unpleasant situations - they will come up eventually, and the longer you ignore them, the harder it will be to deal with when they do come to the surface.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Wow. This must be terrible to go through. </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Not something I&rsquo;d love to do every weekend, but it hasn&rsquo;t been so bad, all things considered. There were some patches that were incredibly rough emotionally, especially towards the beginning, but the past few months I&rsquo;ve found peace and acceptance. We talked through a rough draft of the divorce agreement over a nice bottle of cider, and there aren&rsquo;t really any points of contention. We don&rsquo;t own property, never shared bank accounts or credit cards, don&rsquo;t have kids to worry about, so knock on wood, this should not be a very difficult divorce process legally, considering what we&rsquo;ve seen other people go through. We&rsquo;re even on the same page about custody of the dog.</p>

<p>We also still care about each other very deeply as friends and we both want each other to be happy. Neither one of us is out for blood, and we&rsquo;d like to remain friends. This also makes things easier for you, as you don&rsquo;t have to feel pressured to choose a side.</p>

<p><strong> Q: So when is the actual divorce happening? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> After I move and get settled in, I&rsquo;ll be starting the legal process.</p>

<p><strong> Q: How the hell are you so zen about this? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Lots of therapy, lots of self-reflection, lots of time spent with amazingly supportive friends and family, and lots of hard work in working through the issues I brought to the relationship. Not going to lie - there have been times it&rsquo;s been extremely painful, but I&rsquo;ve uncovered and am working through hurts that I&rsquo;ve been carrying around since way before Brock. Like I said before, emotions that you&rsquo;re trying to hide or have repressed will come up eventually, but meeting them head on and working towards a resolution feels pretty damned fantastic.</p>

<p><strong> Q: Do you regret getting married then? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Absolutely not. While we didn&rsquo;t end up working out as a married couple, we shared many wonderful times together and made a ton of memories that mean a lot to me. I&rsquo;m incredibly thankful for everything Brock has brought to my life and for the time we shared together - he wasn&rsquo;t just a husband, but a best friend. I have learned so much through this whole process, both the marriage and the divorce, and it&rsquo;s made me a better person. Besides, I follow the philosophy that I would never go back and change my past, even the painful parts or things I&rsquo;ve done that I&rsquo;m not so proud of - I wouldn&rsquo;t be who I am and where I am today without everything I&rsquo;ve been through. And for the first time in a long time, I can say I&rsquo;m really rather happy with who and where I am.</p>

<p><strong> Q: So what are you going to do now? </strong> <br>
<strong> A: </strong> Hit restart - it really is never too late.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
