<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Thank You | ebdrummond]]></title>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/blog/tags/thank-you/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-26T23:52:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ebdrummond.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erin Drummond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Whole Mess of Thank Yous]]></title>
    <link href="http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/a-whole-mess-of-thank-yous"/>
    <updated>2013-08-18T17:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ebdrummond.com/2013/08/a-whole-mess-of-thank-yous</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know this is a little late, but better late than never, right?</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a bunch of people I need to thank for their help in supporting me throughout gSchool.  Without their help, it wouldn&rsquo;t have been as rewarding an experience for me; without some of their help, I wouldn&rsquo;t have been able to do it at all.  A huge thank you to everyone listed here, and to a hundred others who helped me along the way.</p>

<ul>
<li>First off, to <a href="http://twitter.com/verdi_michael">Michael Verdi</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/wengzilla">Ed Weng</a> of LivingSocial, for holding the intro to programming workshop that kicked my entire adventure off.  If it hadn&rsquo;t been for their workshop, I would have never realized a) that I could do this and b) how fulfilling it is.</li>
<li>There were a lot of people who helped me out when I got stressed, but <a href="http://twitter.com/edatrix">Lauren Spath Luhring</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/aimzatron">Aimee Maher</a> were the two people who were there closest to me through the most stressful times and put a smile back on my face.  Thanks, ladies!</li>
<li>All of the other <a href="http://people.jumpstartlab.com">gSchool students</a> deserve a big thanks too.  Everyone brought something valuable to the table, and everyone was so helpful - there was a genuine feeling of teamwork throughout the class, and I never felt like anyone was trying to stand up taller by standing on someone else.  I learned so much from all my classmates and hope I helped them learn, too.</li>
<li>Of course, the fabulous <a href="http://jumpstartlab.com/team">gSchool instructors</a> were, well, fabulous throughout the course.  One of the reasons I chose gSchool was because of the quality of the instructors, and they didn&rsquo;t let me down.  They knew their shit, were great at teaching the full group, and were also great at providing one on one help and advice.  <a href="http://twitter.com/kytrinyx">Katrina</a>, especially, took the time to give me a lot of one on one help and also made sure I knew she believed in me, letting me know what I was doing great at and what I needed to work on.  I really appreciate the time they all put into all of us students.</li>
<li>My first mentor, <a href="http://twitter.com/decoydrone">Jim Denton</a>, was amazing.  He was the one who really pushed me and taught me the value of testing by pointing out all the unnecessary headaches I was causing myself.  I really appreciated all the time he spent with me, sometimes an entire afternoon, whipping me into shape and showing me a new way of thinking.</li>
<li>A huge thank you also to my second mentor, <a href="http://twitter.com/tundal45">Ashish Dixit</a>.  Ashish has had awesome ideas for how to refactor some of my gnarliest code, and also introduced me to Table XI - something I can&rsquo;t thank him for enough.  More than that, he&rsquo;s helped point me in the right direction with my jitters on starting my first programming job, and has offered to continue to be my mentor post-gSchool (which is awesome since we&rsquo;ll both be in Chicago!).  He is amazingly smart, so open to helping, and really excited about the broader Ruby community - I feel so lucky to have been teamed up with him.</li>
<li>More than anyone else though, my biggest thanks go out to my wonderful husband, <a href="http://twitter.com/brock">Brock</a>.  I quite literally could not have done this without his support, and support me he did.  He was so excited for me when I decided I wanted to become a programmer, and didn&rsquo;t mind relocating with me to Denver.  Throughout the course he has done most of the housework and took care of the dog when I was studying all the time and helped me out with programming questions throughout the course whenever he could.  He was also so emotionally supportive when I was frustrated, stressed, and drained, and is relocating with me all over again to Chicago without complaint.  I don&rsquo;t know how I got so lucky to have him.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
